[music]
[music] Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hello everybody. Good evening and good
day and welcome back to the Ask a Widget
Show. Today we discuss anything and
everything any topic that you want. You
want to ask me a question, ask me and I
shall answer as long as it's a topic
that I know something about. So before
we start with the Q&A for today for
tonight, let us see who is there on the
live chat. I can see Pulkit Johan.
Pulkit Johan is here. Cavia chef is also
here. Parton 007 Gavia Chef UMXG lol h a
ha haha partnon putin 444 Rahul Dun Mar
Kane good to see you ma'am Mary Kane uh
Monish subarat
riser 199 putin triple 4 gajati jag
jagernad from Odisha geopolitical dub is
here from Indor good to see youai
monish sabrinat
shatabi
Uh Adit Ashwin the scrummer anonymous
R7U5T
real painter arc back to you sir harjun
shishi
siliguri shishi siguri namaste uh sari
arjun once again
namaste
omar kumbar real painter even tide even
tide indeed shukla livea
lanya da
from Jaipur. Namaskar. Vidimar s good to
see you ma'am. Uh Amaya Talpul Guten
Abind
Guten back to you Vikash PJ Chhattany
Manuja Annie 24862. Hello Hindutwa
Matrix has reposted the stream. Thank
you very much on on X Gartik and Mahita
Bushetti. Hello Random Skull. Hi Mac 4.
Namaste Ragubir Salanki Daria
from Jaipur. Yes, Canel. Alukbat Dak
Abhishek Vik PJ Rahul Hintani from
Mumbai. Namaste. Shrih Hari Arun once
again. Mlevin good to see you. Mlevin uh
Apura Adidasi
hello Siddi Shetty. Hi Karab Mahita
Bushi Omniv Amisha Mishra. Hello. Hello.
Good to see you, ma'am. Chaitanya once
again. Gajat Deva from Odisha Dana.
Okay, I think we're repeating a few of
these names. Um,
uh, who else? Who else? Canel, Vikash,
PJ, Adat, Ashwani, and everyone else.
Hit Bora, History Go, Vignesh, Kohli,
Nirvana, Shanks, Kunicha, Sagar, Kare,
Priyanka Jalia, good evening. Priyanka G
has set alarm, an alarm at 8:00 p.m.
Thank you very much. uh Manish Hans
Nirvana Shang once again and everyone
else. Okay. Okay.
Let's take some questions. What
questions do we have today? This fine
evening. What questions do we have? Let
us see.
Uh first of all, Cav Kavia Chef has
become a member, a new member. Thank you
very much. Cavia, welcome to the
membership of the channel. That is very
kind of you. Thank you very much.
Partinan says
what? What's this? Than original
followers. Second question. Okay, maybe
it's a mixup of two questions. I asked
this too late yesterday. Okay, why are
Amish people living like 12th century
today in 2025? Who are the Amish people
is the question that we have to address.
First of all, the Amish people
are a very conservative uh well group of
people who live in the United States.
What part of the United States escapes
me? Let us quickly Google that. See the
Amish people, they are originally Swiss
German most likely. Okay. And they
practice Baptist or Anabaptist
Christianity. Anabaptist Christianity,
whatever that means. I am not an expert
in that. So they practice a certain form
or flavor or variant of Christianity. Uh
and because of the form of Christianity
they practice, they are very
conservative.
Their values are super conservative.
They wear very plain dresses. Uh they
educate their children up to the eighth
standard. Nothing nothing more than
that. They do not use uh
motorized vehicles. They use horsedrawn
buggies. Um
they they marry young. Then they have
all these you know uh what you could say
kind of antiquated
ways of life. Their way of life is quite
you could say antiquated. It's like 19th
or 18th century way of life. That sort
of thing. Where do the Amish people
live? That's that's an interesting uh
point that we should look into. Amish
people. Amish. Amish
people.
Where do they live? What part of the
United States? Pennsylvania, Ohio, and
Indiana.
So yeah, this is this is going to give
us a good uh representation of where the
Amish people live. So they kind of
spread out across the mostly the
northern and eastern part of the United
parts of the United States, but
obviously there are some of them in
other parts as well. And as you can see,
they, you know, they dress very
conservatively. It looks like this is a
a set from a period movie, that sort of
thing. They have these horsedrawn
buggies or carriages
and uh children as you can see I mean
you can't see from here but they are
educated until I think the eighth
standard. Um the dresses are very plain
very simple. Uh they believe in having
large families.
Um I'm not sure if this is very Amish
but okay this is definitely Amish. Uh
kids are often barefoot which is not a
bad thing. Yeah. um and so on. As you
can see, this is the kind of you know
lifestyle they have. It's a it's a
pretty interesting uh maybe slightly
anacronistic lifestyle. So why do they
live in this manner? It's because of
their belief system. Uh Anabaptist
Christianity. Let's let's look at let's
find out what that is. Anabaptist
uh Anabaptist.
Anabaptist meaning. What does it mean?
Radical reformers during the 16th
century Protestant revol revolution who
believed baptism could be only for
consenting adult believers not infants.
Strict biblical interpretation
separation of church and state. Pacifism
communal living. Yeah. All of these
values are you know uh embodied in the
Amish lifestyle. So it's Protestantism,
Protestantism,
Protest, they are Protestants,
uh Protestant Reformation. So they seem
to be similar to the Hugenoths, the
Calvinists kind of you maybe
um origin began in Switzerland and
Germany around 1525
with leaders like Konad, Grebel, etc. So
the answer to your question is they have
this kind of lifestyle because of their
belief system. The kind of beliefs they
have very literal and very strict
interpretation of the Bible and so on.
Parthanon says why are converted
people of Abra Abrahamic faith more
religious? See when you convert to a
different faith, let's say you born into
so and so religion or culture or
civilization and then you decide for
whatever reason to convert to to a
different let's say a foreign religion
then
when you convert willingly or maybe
unwillingly whatever to a foreign
religion. If you convert willingly then
you do it with a tremendous amount of
enthusiasm right it's something new and
you believe it's it's a better way of
living. So that's why you are very
zealous about you know practicing all
the tenets and whatever of this new
religion probably the Abrahamic
religions because in eastern religions
Hinduism Buddhism the Dharmic religions
even Shinto in Japan Tangism what they
callism in Mongolian so on there's no
conversion there's no conver there's no
system of conversion you want to believe
it you believe it you want to live that
lifestyle you live live that lifestyle
but there's no pressure to convert into
or convert out of the thing the
Abrahamic religions are very strict and
if you convert to that you're going to
be very zealous in the way you uh you
know live your life and if you've been
forced to convert then [laughter]
those who have forc you to convert are
going to ensure that you are you stick
to the uh tenetss and precepts of the
religion extra carefully and extra
strictly otherwise well you may not want
to do the otherwise thing so that's why
yeah and the Abrahamic religions are are
are are pretty
you know their their lifestyle is often
non-negotiable and if you don't do that
then you may have the inquisition that
is dumped upon your head uh that that
happened in the last 500 years and in
certain other religions it's something
nastier than than the inquisition would
happen because of these reasons um
people who belong to Abra who convert to
Abrahamic faiths are typically more
religious than people who are born into
these faiths
The Nvidia CEO says UMXG Lolaha. The
Nvidia CEO stated that the Linux kernel
is unsafe. Is this based on genuine
security concerns or influenced by
limited support for open source? I'm not
sure. I have not looked into this. I was
not even aware that Jensen Huang has
said that the Linux kernel is unsafe.
Did he say that? Okay, let's see. Uh
Jensen Hang
Linux
unsafe.
Why does blah blah blah? Neither Jensen
Huang nor Nvidia have stated that Linux
is inherently unsafe. Okay, that's what
the AI says. But do we have any news?
Nvidia CEO anthrop. No, that's
different.
Nvidia. Okay, first of all, when you say
Nvidia CEO, are we talking about Jensen
Wang or is it somebody else? Yeah, he's
the CEO. So, looks like he hasn't said
such a thing. Let's go into the news
portion. Google blah blah.
AI taking jobs. Nope.
Nope. Doesn't look like he has said any
such thing.
And even if he has said this, I am not
aware of what is the reason in case he
has said that. But as far as I can see,
uh that hasn't happened. So
UMXG Laha says thoughts on NRA Arya. Who
is Nira Arya?
I don't know who Narya is. Is it an
entertainer? Is it some historian? Is it
a scientist? Is it an entrepreneur? Uh
let's find out who is NRA Arya.
NR Arya who is the first woman spy etc.
Well I'm not aware of this person. Yeah.
Okay. I must have seen this lady's uh
photo. This is obviously all
okay this lady. So I I'm not aware of
her life story and career and also I
don't have any thoughts about her.
Sorry.
Uh, UMXG LHA says Thailand army destroys
Hindu state deity thoughts. Unfortunate.
I mean, I've seen that video of the of a
bulldozer bringing um what it was a
statue of which god. I'm not sure which
god it was, but why do that? I mean,
maybe the the Cambodians built the
statue, but uh the god is part of the
shared culture between Thailand and
Cambodia. Why do they have to destroy
it? I'm not sure. So I think it's
terribly unfortunate. I mean there's no
need to do that.
Uh polar royalism says all lot of
foreign powers in Bangladesh
example MI6 CIA. Uh is there a question
here? Is there a comment?
Obviously the you've had a regime change
that's happened in Bangladesh.
Bangladesh is now East Pakistan and the
orchestrator of the regime change is
obviously the United States of America
and u you know if you are the US you
would also do such things to uh promote
and safeguard your interests in various
parts of the world so that's why they've
done this and it would not be MI6 MI6
MI6 what is MI6 MI6 is the British spy
agency right
I'm sure they still are quite capable
I'm sure they have a few 007 agents or
whatever But it would be the CIA, not
the MI6 mostly that's involved in these
matters. MI6 is now a junior agency
compared to the CIA.
UMXG lol haha says ex Supreme Court
judge Katu
says all ministers are rogues and
Rascal's thought on this ex. I have no
thoughts on exchudes. Sorry. I don't
discuss internal matters in India. I
discuss history, geopolitics, science. I
stay outside of India. I don't discuss
Indian politics, Indian judiciary,
Indian this that thoughts on this
person. Sorry. No comments about judges.
Not my
not my cup of tea. I am not talking
about these things. All right. Parthonon
says, "How did Arabs and Turks get rid
of black slaves?" That's number one.
Second, why didn't No. Why didn't
Confederates do the same or worse when
they knew that they were going to lose?
Okay, let's first talk about the Arabs
and Turks. Black slaves. What did the
Arabs and Turks do to black slaves? They
castrated them.
They would see when it came when it
comes to black slaves, they would
typically enslave black men. I'm not
aware of black women, African origin
women being enslaved. As far as I know,
that would be that would not have been a
very uh common practice. They typically
enslaved African origin men and those
men were typically castrated so that
they would not pass on their genetics,
their DNA to future generations.
That's what they did to African origin
or black male slaves. So they probably
enslaved hundreds of thousands maybe
millions of African uh origin black you
know male slaves. None of those have
been able to pass on their genetics.
They were castrated used for labor and
then they would die off at whatever age.
That's what happened. Now the question
second question is why didn't
confederates do the same or worse? To
whom?
To whom
when they knew they were going to lose?
To slaves.
Why would you do that?
I am not sure I follow the logic. So,
the Confederates are about to lose the
Civil War. Okay. So, when you're losing,
what should you do? Should you just uh
kill off the slaves?
I I don't I don't get it. I'm I'm not
sure what the logic is. So if I am the
confederate, I'm fighting a war because
I want slavery. Now I'm losing the war
and I'm about to lose. So should I go
and kill all the slaves? What what will
I gain from that?
I don't get it. So uh Monish Sabrinat
says pranam well pranam g pranam back to
you. Thank you. Monish Sabrinat says in
ancient gurukuls how was bullying
prevented? I have absolutely no idea but
typically the guruguls were run by the
gurus
and the gurus would ensure that there
would be shishtachar in the gurukul. See
bullying happens when children are
typically unsupervised.
So in today's classrooms you have 50
students 70 80 100 students sometimes
and there's one teacher for for this
entire bunch of kids and I'm talking
about the Indian education system the
stupidly rotten Indian education system
so when you have this situation
a lot of the time the students will be
unsupervised there'll be too many
students too few too few teachers and
there'll be you know periods there'll be
times when there's a break between
classes or lectures or or periods like
they say or there could be the
intermission or what recreation
lunch break what whatever it's called
recess recess that's once again when the
kids are outside so when you have so
many kids with so many students you're
going to have some some of the you know
there's a small certain amount certain
percentage of every population that has
these tendencies so that's why you will
have bullying but in the guru schools
you the the number of students was
limited because you had so many guru
schools across India India and the
person who was the guru would know how
to control children and they would
impart the right values. That's why most
likely bullying would never have
happened in a in gurugul. See bullying
is an antisocial activity. It's an
uncultured univilized activity. You
cannot expect that to happen in
gurugals. If any student behave that way
they would face consequences.
So yeah, we have lost the records of the
past, but uh that's what I imagine would
have happened. Okay. Parthonon says in
1865, why didn't the USA ban guns to
prevent civil wars?
It's part of the constitution.
Okay, let's let's look into this. Okay.
Uh,
US Constitution,
gun rights.
So, second amendment. The US
Constitution second amendment protects
the right to keep and bear arms. Um, so
it's part of of the US Constitution and
I'm sure it's not that easy to amend.
How many constit US constitutions
constitution? How many amendments?
How many amendments? 27 in the Indian
constitution since 1945. How many
amendments? I don't even know. Indian
constitution. Let's find out.
106 amendments. The Indian constitution
is like a patchwork thing. The US
constitution when if amendments are a
very serious thing. So it's it's part of
US culture. It's part of what the United
States is. You don't do that. So, you
know,
that's why they I suppose it would be
very difficult. I'm not sure what the
process or procedure is to amend the
constitution, but I suppose you would
need a lot of support from the various
political factions and all. And I'm sure
it was not that easy and nobody ever
thought about it because it's part of
the the American ethos, gun rights, the
right to bear arms. That is an
unalienable part of American culture.
not possible to ban ban it who who
decides to ban it who decides that who
dares to do that
says the university where I'm studying
there are many students who are doing
smoking drinking and many other bad
things all of all other bad things sadly
younger batches is it due to a lack of
discipline seeing many horrible cases
makes me upset daily
why do you see this why does this happen
well When I was a student,
there were students who were doing the
same things.
I suppose 30 years before I was a
student, I suppose many students would
have been doing similar things. See, the
first thing we have to understand
these things aren't illegal,
right? Smoking and drinking isn't
neither smoking nor drinking is illegal
uh in most parts of the country. I don't
think there's any state in India where
smoking is illegal. Drinking is illegal
in a few states here and there.
Uh but even in those states we know how
things go
and you know smoking and drinking I mean
alcohol and tobacco are reasonably
readily not reasonably they're
plentifully available legally
and they don't cost a lot. I mean
alcohol can cost a lot or it can be
really cheap
and and these days people have more
disposable income.
Uh so I suppose that's one of the
reasons why and and you know young
people have always had this this this
desire to you know kind of experiment
with things and you know try and test
the boundaries of what is acceptable
what is not. people want to try new
things when when they when they are new
adults they have newly become adult or
whatever. So that's another that's that
could be a contributing factor and of
course there are plenty of people who
will never touch alcohol or tobacco and
that's great and that's ideally how
everyone should do should be. So it
depends on uh
your values your upbringing
uh your personality and so on.
Uh I would say look as far as people
don't do hard drugs which all right I
suppose hard drugs obviously can be very
dangerous very damaging ideally nobody
should do these things but that's just
how it is so is it due to a lack of
discipline is it due to something else
it's due to a variety of factors and
there's nothing we can do to prevent it
unless the government decides to ban all
these things which would not be a very
popular move yeah because historically
if you even if you look at Indian
history Alcohol has been a thing. Um
people have smoked not tobacco. Tobacco
comes from comes from the Americas but
um people would smoke marijuana on
Shivatri and all. So these things have
kind of been part of our history and
yeah it's it's just what it is.
Okay. Shatabish says, "Your thoughts on
andromeda paradox as a consequence of
special relativity might be an aspect of
reality being a simulation as now itself
isn't universal."
Andromeda paradox.
What is the Andromeda paradox?
Andromeda paradox. What is that? Let's
find out.
Andromeita paradox. Okay, Sabina has
done a video on this. Okay, let's find
out.
What is the Andromeda paradox?
Androme, can you blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Not sure what this is.
Uh, let's go back and see. Special
relativity. What is the Oh, that's the
same one. Okay.
Um,
okay. Wolf ram
demonstrations project. What is this? It
doesn't have a description.
Mandai Supreme Galactic Council. Blur.
Do we have a description of what this is
somewhere? I'm not watching a video
right now.
Okay. Maybe this.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Okay. It's a
thought experiment proposed by
philosopher Roger Penrose based on okay
special relativity one of the most
mindbending paradoxes it's not a
[snorts] physical
consider two people Alice and Ofia of
course Al is and Bob starting or not
they are trying to determine if a major
event for example an alien invasion is
happening right now from the Andromea
galaxy which is about 2.5 million lighty
years away according to special
relativity the concept of simultaneously
simultaneity is not universal we know
that okay so is standing still and
defines a plane of simultaneity that
says the andromeda inversion is
happening Right now, Bob is walking
briskly away from Alice at a mere 100
few hundred miles per hour. Small
non-relativistic speed and so on and so
forth. Conclusion:
The tilt is enough to make Bob's
present.
Okay. What's the big deal?
Uh, if the invasion is fixed the
invasion to
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Listen, I'm not
going to go through the details right
now and do all that. What's the What's
the question? My thoughts. Well, I
haven't studied this.
people come up with different ways of
testing general special relativity
and and um you know bringing out
interesting uh aspects of it and so on.
So I haven't studied this specific
paradox. We know the twin paradox we
know the grandfather paradox and so on.
I haven't looked into this. It will take
me some time to read it. So let's keep
moving on. Uh but see
is this an aspect of reality being a
simulation as now is no it's not non
it's just encoded in special relativity
for any two observers what is now may
not be the same
simultaneity itself is relative so
that's all part of special relativity
there's no that doesn't in that doesn't
indicate that you know we are part we
are living in a simulation not at all
okay sabirinat says I'm seeing people
from a batch and also in junior batches
go into relationships do all the things
and leave. Why do these people take the
aspects of life these aspects of life
casually and tag the rest as losers who
don't do these things? I don't know. I
don't care.
I don't think this is a good way to
live.
I don't think I mean animals live in
this manner. For some people you may
feel like you know you are great if you
have like 15 different girlfriends of
over a period of two years or whatever
and similarly for girls it's like
conquest. It's not conquest. You're
cheapening yourself.
Maybe it indicates that you are
physically attractive and so on but at
the end of the day what's the point of
all this? So I am not
a fan of this sort of lifestyle. Why do
they do it? There may be various reasons
for that. Maybe it's insecurity. Maybe
it's a desire to prove that I am so
great and I can get any kind of person
and so on. Whatever it is, it it stems
from some form of insecurity deep deep
within you. And people who are insecure,
they they they overcompensate in a
variety of ways.
Um
the long run, I don't think it's it's
good for you. I think it's damaging for
you.
uh not just for you it may not be
damaging for you physically but it may
it will be damaging for you deep inside
at the level of the soul lives I would
say uh so my point is I don't want to
get into why do people behave in such
manner that's their problem
I would recommend don't do these things
you know one of the greatest qualities
that a person can have
is is standards
and one of The aspects of having high
standards is to be loyal to one person.
That is the one of the foundational
pillars of civilized life of
civilization itself.
Uh so yeah that's what I can say. Ritik
Pawar says why are coups rare these
days? Well in 2022 you had a coup in
West Pakistan. Imran Khan was ousted and
this fellow Sharif Shabbaz Sharif was
parachuted into position. He is a
puppet. In 2024,
9 months after I predicted that there
was a coup in East Pakistan, in
Bangladesh and Shik Hassina was ousted
and Bangladesh has now been transformed
into East Pakistan. Are coups really
rare these days. There have been coups
in Africa,
right? In
Burkina, it's not like coups are rare.
It's like coups do happen but they kind
of stay under the radar and often the
media portrays these coups as democratic
transitions and genz revolution and
whatnot. There's been a coup in Nepal
also. So coups aren't rare then you know
military coups well military coups are
more frequent less rare in Africa
um in East Pakistan, West Pakistan these
have been military coups by the way.
Shir Kasina was given an ultimatum of 45
minutes. Leave in 45 minutes. Leave the
country in 45 minutes or else. Who gave
that ultimatum? Was it the so-called
student leaders? No, it was the
Bangladeshi military. So, please
understand at the at the root of
everything is the military.
Okay. Gapati says, "What do you think
about
YT people, YouTube people cosplaying as
Hindus trying to portray Jesus as Hindu
god?
If I whitey is white, what do you think
about what do I think about white people
cosplaying as Hindus trying to portray
Jesus as Hindu gods as a Hindu god?
There are plenty of people who do that.
Then a lot of Indians get fooled by
these people.
You know there are there are some
accounts on Twitter
some some people some persons
often female. Yeah. Because it works.
um who have on X on Twitter in the on
the header image there's an image of a
Hindu god and Jesus together and that
lady says that Hindu that uh Jesus is
the same as a Hindu god and so on and
lots of people are following this lady
[clears throat]
and u
there is another person on Twitter who
even I was following until
uh yeah
These people they their objective is to
fool Hindus
and
By fooling Hindus they want to
subliminally do some messaging that that
will unconsciously be absorbed by Hindus
that sort of thing. Yeah. So uh and u
this goes very deep. It's not just
individuals, it's organizations too that
have potentially
been compromised perhaps.
And yeah, that that goes very deep
very deep indeed. Yeah. And such
organizations may have millions,
tens of millions of followers perhaps
where whether it's India, whether it's
other parts of the world and so on. So
yeah, the rot goes deep, deep, deep,
deep, deep, deep. The objective at the
end of the day is to erase Indian
civilization.
The scrummer, the scrummer says, how do
we measure time traveled by light coming
from interstellar objects? effect of
gravitational lensing on its accuracy.
How do we measure
the time traveled by light coming from
interstellar objects?
So essentially you are asking how do we
measure the distance
of let's say a star from here
right because the distance of a star
let's say a star is 78 light years away
it means that light has taken 78 years
that's the time light has taken to
travel from the star to here so what
you're actually asking is how do we
measure the distance to interstellar
objects because the time traveled by
light is a reflection of the distance.
If we know exactly how long light
traveled, we will know the distance.
So there are multiple ways of doing it.
Uh one of the ways of measuring the
distance a galaxy is from here. Let's
say that we we have discovered a galaxy.
Okay, we have we have discovered a
galaxy somewhere but we don't know where
it is. We don't quite know how far it is
from here. So where for star for stars
there is the parallax method. For
galaxies there is a very
accurate method which is uh type 1A
supernovas.
So type 1A supernovas are called
standard can candles because they always
have the same luminosity
and we know how luminosity luminosity
varies with distance
right. So when we detect a type 1A
supernova which is not very rare in a
galaxy several times a year year you
will have a type 1 a supernova that goes
off in a in any galaxy. So when you
detect that you all you have to do is to
measure its luminosity
and by and there's there's a clear
correlation between luminosity and
distance and that's how you can
determine how far the thing is the
galaxy is and so on. There are various
ways of doing it. I to explain all of
these in detail would take a lot of time
but one of the best ways of doing it is
by using type 1A supernovas. How do type
1A supernovas happen? That's when you
have a neutron star orbiting a standard
um
standard star. Okay. And um no is it?
It's white dwarf. When you have a white
type 1 a supernova happens when you have
white dwarf orbiting a regular star and
the white dwarf is sucking in gas
from the regular star. Yes. And then
eventually it crosses the chundra
shakhar limit and goes boom boom. So is
it white dwarf? Is it is it uh neutron?
It's probably white dwarf. Type one a
supernova
and then white dwarf. Exactly. Yeah. So
it crosses the chandra limit and then
goes boom boom. It it then it
it uh under goes the catastrophic
explosion called a type 1 supernova. So
because we know exactly what the chundra
shakar limit is even if you put one
spoonful of more material into the star
it's going to go boom. So that's why we
know exactly how much luminosity the
supernova will have. And you know that's
how we can measure the distance
estimate. I mean yeah calculate the
distance. Okay, Gapati says, "The
previous question I asked were is that I
wanted to ask last week, but YouTube
super chat censored it. Finally found a
workaround by using ridiculous spellings
to bypass." Well, YouTube is YouTube.
I suppose it has certain words, certain
keywords that it would like to censor
and and cut out and not allow you to
post. that I've heard this uh complaint
multiple times from my viewers that
YouTube often censors
some super chats or regular chats and
you have to find some some workaround
for that using ridiculous spelling
spellings or something like that. So
well yeah
and the level of censorship raises many
questions. It does.
It does.
What can I say? It is what it is. It's
look at the end of the day it's a
private company. It's an American
company. It's not an Indian company. And
they have their interests. YouTube is an
advertising platform. And YouTube is an
American platform. And because of these
two factors, there's going to be certain
kinds of censorship, which is to be
expected. Yeah. So I I don't complain
about it. It is what it is. You either
use the platform or you don't. But you
don't complain. So I don't complain.
Mary Kane, thank you very much, ma'am. I
hope you're doing great. Thank you so
much. Good to always good to have you as
a as as my viewer.
Ritik Paw says what is best for a
country a completely sovereign but poor
country for example India. Second a
non-s sovereign but developed rich
nation for example Germany and Japan.
So take the example of Germany. Germany
has been under foreign occupation since
1945. Maybe none of you realize this,
but Germany has been under permanent
American military occupation since 1945.
Multiple military bases operated by
Americans and run by Americans with
American soldiers permanently stationed
there, American fighter jets stationed
there, etc. Um the German constitution
was essentially written under the
supervision which means under the
supervision of Americans which means it
was essentially written by Americans.
Um
and the nation is essentially controlled
by the United States when it comes to
and and today what do you see in
Germany? immigration and all kinds of
issues.
The economy is being
def I mean it's it's going backwards
recession all sorts of issues no proper
leadership German leaders you you can't
be German German leader a German a
German chancellor if you are in any way
not aligned with the United States when
it comes to Japan it's even worse more
than 130 permanent US military bases on
Japanese soil
The Japanese economy was slowly
wrecked
1980s onwards by who? By the Americans.
The Japanese constitution is written by
the Americans. The Japanese economy is
run by the Americans. Japanese foreign
policy is run by the Americans. Japanese
defense policy is run by the Americans.
Japan's TFR has
undergone catastrophic contraction.
So you so Germany and Japan are examples
of non-s sovereign nations that are de
developed and rich but their entire fate
lies in the hands of the foreign
overlord.
Japan I am not sure what kind of future
it even has today.
They are now importing hundreds of
thousands of Bangladeshes and whatnot
because their population is just
it's it's it's collapsing.
It's it's it's terrible for Japan. So
if you are a non-s sovereign but rich
nation, if you're a citizen of a
non-soverver but rich nation, you're
going to have a good lifestyle as long
as the overlord allows that. But then
they will decide to flood your nation
with hundreds of millions, hundreds of
thousands of Bangladeshes. Then what
happens to your lifestyle? You have no
control over what what happens to you?
That's terrible.
uh in our case India completely
sovereign nation but poor country. Yeah.
But our our GDP is is rising. We are
working as as hard as we can to grow our
GDP and it's projected to India is
projected to become a most more or less
a medium in income nation in about 15
years or so right GDP per capita. uh
from that perspective 15 20 years
maximum we also have Bangladeshes all
over the place which is a failure of the
government it has nothing to do with
sovereignty or poverty or whatever so I
would say what is best for a country is
to be a rich powerful and sovereign
nation and if you are a poor but
sovereign nation you should work has as
hard as possible to become wealthy as
soon as possible that is what is best
for a country and that depends on the
quality of the leadership and the
quality of the institutions and
governance systems.
So in India we have multiple challenges
because of all that. All right.
Uh there Uber Mench says I am in class
11th CS computer science stream is it
CS? I want to join the army but family
isn't supporting. I have a single
mother. What do I do? How do I prepare?
Okay. So you are in class 11 which means
how old would you be?
15 16 somewhere around that age. CS
means computer science most likely or
you want to join the army but the family
isn't supporting. You have a single mom.
What should you do? Well, at the end of
the day,
you have you should I would say
do what you think is best for yourself.
I don't think joining the army is a bad
thing. You can have a great life, a
great career if you join the army. If
that's something you desire, then you
know what? I can understand why your mom
would not like it perhaps because it's
kind of risky. You're going to have to
use weapons. You may have to fight
Pakistanis and whatnot in someday. So
it's understandable that your mom would
be kind of not
comfortable with that. I can understand
that especially when there are other
avenues that you could go into.
So maybe so what you should do is maybe
you should try and put yourself in her
shoes and maybe think from her her
perspective too and and test if that
changes your mind. And if it doesn't
change your mind, maybe you can try and
convince your mom. Then you know what?
It's not that dangerous a lifestyle. And
maybe and so many people join the armed
forces and they do really well.
So,
so try and see things from her
perspective. But if you still are sure
that you want to join the armed forces,
then I think you have a couple of years,
maybe one year at least to convince her.
So that's what I would suggest you do.
But at the end of the day, I'll tell you
something. See, if you know what you
want to do, but you sacrifice that to
please your mom, then how will you feel
about your mom in 20 years? You will
always have this feeling of bitterness
towards her. Right?
In 20 years, 30 years, 40 years, 50
years, you will always have this
permanent sense of bitterness that your
mom made you sacrifice what you really
wanted to do to do in life. Do you want
to have that long-term bitterness
towards your mom?
I would say you don't want to have it.
So, in case you don't want to have it,
then do what you what you feel is right
for you. Even if your mom disagrees,
right? That's what I would suggest. But
of course, be don't be harsh towards
her. Don't be unkind. Don't be rude. All
that. Try and explain to her
lovingly that this is what I believe is
the right path for me and I think it's a
great career. Try and do that. I hope it
works out for you sir. Thank you. All
the best.
Nagarand Shenoi says namaskarum. Thank
you. Namaskarum. Can you please tell us
anything about Kakatia dynasty? I'm
not the I'm I'm not the right person for
this. I haven't studied the Kakari
dynasty in any
great detail. Yeah. So, sorry. I'm I'm
really sorry. I There are so many
incredibly interesting dynasties with
with such rich history and very,
you know, largely unknown histories. So
many of these amazing dynasties
have ruled various parts of India and
our historians have written very little
about these and so many of them these
dynasties contributed so much to our
culture and civilization and history and
they're they're they are unsung. So I'm
sure the kakatias are one of those
dynasties but I haven't studied their
history in any amount of detail so I
won't be able to answer your question.
Very sorry about that.
Nidi says, Nidi Roses says, I was
shocked that Christmas is a stolen pagan
festival from ancient Rome like
Satnelia.
Is true they stole everything. Will they
do that to Diwali in the future? See,
I'll tell you what. Um,
it is said that um, Mr. Mr. Christ, Mr.
Jesus was born on December 25, but
that's it's just a stolen pagan
festival. See, Christianity
was see the Romans, it is said they
persecuted Christianity and they
persecuted Christians, right? But they
did not do that to Jew to Jews. Why is
that? It's because Judaism was an older
religion older than Rome itself. Judaism
has had no interest
in converting Roman citizens to to
Judaism. And Judaism did not pose a
threat to the social and imperial fabric
of of the Roman Empire. That's why the
Romans were perfectly happy with
Judaism. They did not persecute Jews for
practicing their religion.
They only persecuted Jews when the Jews
tried to rebel against Roman occupation.
It had nothing to do with religion. But
the Romans persecuted Christians and
they tried to stamp out Christianity.
Did not work. Why is because
Christianity was this
new artificial cult
that was militaristic in nature, that
was political in nature. It it it
represented a threat to law and order
and culture and civilization. Christians
liked to destroy Roman polytheistic
temples, desecrate temples, disfigure
deities, idols of deities. They liked to
murder mathematician lady mathematicians
on the streets, tear them to pieces and
they sought Christians sought to take
over power from Rome. And they succeeded
eventually. And how did
the early Christians impose Christianity
across Europe? By force. And then to to
ensure that the former pagans continued
practicing Christianity, they co-opted
the the the polytheistic festivals and
gave them Christian connotations. So one
of these is obviously Christmas. So now
there is this big u campaign going on in
India right now to Christianize India.
Billions of dollars are being poured
into India every year from the west and
other parts of the world. And there are
industrial scale efforts going on to uh
to re-engineer the demographics of
India. You can see what's happening in
certain parts of India very clearly.
Right? So if they do succeed in doing to
India what they did to Europe, then they
will steal Diwali also and they will
give Diwali a new name and they will
have a lunar Christian calendar based on
the Hindu calendar and they will
repurpose all the ancient thousands
millennia old Hindu traditions and say
that these were all Christian
traditions. That's what they will
eventually do. So yeah, if we allow this
to happen, they will steal Diwali too.
Fast snail says history on 1976
Venezuela oil nationalization. ah I
don't know
it's a very particular specific topic
that I haven't studied so can't say sir
very sorry
um brown leprechaun says I work as a
senior data security consultant and
currently reside in Ireland I will
obtain an Irish passport by 2028
in your opinion is it a good idea to
move to Switzerland
Um,
if you have an Irish passport, is it uh
easy to move to Switzerland? Because the
Swiss, as far as I know and understand,
the Swiss historically are not very
welcoming of immigration.
If you have
decent amounts of money, you can buy
property in certain parts of Switzerland
like Montre, which is on the eastern end
of Lac Limo or or Lake Geneva. That's
one part of Switzerland where you can
buy property.
uh you can buy commercial property in
various parts of Switzerland. But my
question is what I'm not able to see is
whether you want to become a Swiss
citizen or you want to just reside in
Switzerland. If you have an Irish
passport, I suppose it will be pretty
easy for you to uh reside in
Switzerland.
Um
and if you can get a job in Switzerland,
it'll be even easier. Um so is it a good
idea to move? Okay. So, first of all,
let's say it's possible, it's feasible
for you to do that, to move to
Switzerland. Is it a good idea? Well,
it's a good idea if you have the money.
Switzerland is an extremely expensive
country to live in. Everything is way
higher price than in Ireland or any
other part of most other parts of
Europe. Very high uh cost of living.
Okay. apartments. If you want to buy an
apartment, I mean, maybe $100,000 per
square meter or something. I'm just
guessing some parts of Switzerland,
everything is super expensive. A a
bottle of Aion will cost way more than
it'll cost in Ireland. So, so I would
say if you have the money, it's a great
place to live in. It's kind of boring,
but that's a good thing actually. It
doesn't have this roaring light night
life and whatever you find in New York
City or San Francisco. or whatever. It's
a very laid-back, conservative country,
a very pretty country. So, if you have
the means to live there, I would say
certainly I don't think it's a bad idea
to move to Switzerland. It's a great
place to live in. Um, yeah. So, it all
depends on how much how much can you
afford to spend per year on your as as
living expenses. If you can afford that,
outstanding. Great. Okay. Srishi
siliguri shishi siliguri says when I
research deeply and connect dots. I feel
huge joy as if I have discovered
something but but I get stuck in that
feeling and pause my work losing days or
months. Okay, why does this happen and
how to move ahead?
Well, so when you research something
deeply and you connect dots because the
more you research the more the
connections the more connections you'll
be able to discover. Sometimes the
connections just suddenly pop up in your
head and you oh it's like wow wow I
didn't realize that. Yes there there are
all these hidden connections that I that
were lying in plain sight but I could
not see them before but now I can see
them. So that gives you this feeling of
yeah joy, pleasure, euphoria whatever
right yeah you've obviously discovered
something hidden right when you are able
to connect dots right but you get stuck
in that feeling and pause your work and
lose days and months. Why does this
happen? Well, I don't know.
Um, I've also had the experience of
discovering hidden connections. It it
does it give me joy? It does give me
joy. I I I like the feeling. Do I pause
my work? I actually like want to go
deeper and redouble my efforts.
So, I'm not sure why it happens. See, so
no two people are the same. I may
experience this in a certain way. You
may experience it in a different way. A
third person may experience it in a
different way. And my reaction will be
different from yours which will be
different from a third person. Why does
this happen?
Maybe you
want to celebrate
the fact that you've discovered
something and maybe you want to enjoy
the the joy of of this discovery.
So uh I cannot speculate truly about why
does it why do you have this reaction
that you pause the work and you lose
days or months but the question is how
to move ahead. So um
you what I would recommend is that you
should have a rule for yourself that
when I make a discovery like this I will
give myself 60 minutes to jo to dance in
joy and to celebrate that in in whatever
way you like and then you'll get back to
work. It's all about you know having a
standard operating procedure SOP. that's
having and it's it's easier to have a
standard operating pro procedure than to
rely on willpower and discipline.
So make a make a set of rules for
yourself that when I discover something
like this, it's a hidden connection.
I've connected some dots that are that
others can't see. Then I will celebrate
for 60 minutes, maybe one day or
whatever. You decide what time period
and then you get back to work. Maybe
that SOP will work for you. You know,
processes always translate into
discipline. So maybe you can create this
kind of standard operating procedure for
yourself. All right, ma'am. All the
best. Tjas mi thank you very much tas g
and drove me the live game says what is
going to ultimately happen in Bangladesh
okay you're asking me to predict the
future ultimate future in Bangladesh see
ultimately what's going to happen that's
in about 5 billion years the sun will
become a red giant it will engulf the
earth which means that Bangladesh the
Indian subcontinent everything will melt
and [laughter]
we will become part of the sun. That is
the ultimate fate. And eventually the
sun will shed its outer layers. It will
become what's called a planetary
planetary nebula. It will not go
supernova. And at the at the center, you
will have a white dwarf. And that's and
in hundreds of billions of years, it's
going to become a black dwarf. So that's
what's ultimately going to happen. The
ultimate fate of our solar system, the
ultimate fate of the universe, I can't
really say. But what's going to happen
in Bangladesh? ultimately what what is
the meaning of ultimate is the question
you I'm I'm trying to point out when we
say ultimately what do we mean by that
next 5 years next 10 years next next
3,000 years what is ultimate
so I can speculate as to what could
happen the coming couple of years
Bangladesh will become more see there's
going to be an election in Bangladesh
sometime next year that election is
going to be interesting
When's the next election in Bangladesh?
Let's see. Let's find out. Uh when is
when when is the next election in Bang
Bangladesh?
When is it? 12th of February 2026.
So that election
will either lead to Bangladesh becoming
even more anti-India
or maybe depending on the outcome of the
election it could stop being so
anti-India.
But overall Bangladesh is going the way
of Pakistan. It's becoming it's
reverting to its East Pakistan status
the way things are right now. So Hindus
are in danger now. I don't know what the
percentage of Hindus is right now but in
20 years it could be what what you have
in Pakistan maybe 2% or something. It
could end up like that. There are
various possibilities that are open. I
can't predict what's going to happen.
Depends on so many different variables
and parameters.
Okay. Um Hit Dia says,
"Please complete the remaining book for
reviews.
I have got a million books. [laughter]
I've got a million books out here. I
must have done quite a few more than a
dozen book reviews. And each time I was
reviewing like five, six books.
That process can take forever. Maybe
I'll do a few more. Maybe I should first
put out those book reviews in the form
of separate short clips. That's the
first thing I can do. And then maybe
I'll look into doing more book reviews.
Um the the remaining I don't know what
the remaining number is. There is no
remaining number. The remaining number
is infinity for me book reviews wise cuz
yeah as long as I'm here on the planet
I'm going to be reading books.
Uh oiler says every Indian now thinks
that they are an expert in geopolitics.
Well
Indians I think now have a much better
understanding of international relations
and what we call geopolitics than let's
say in 2021.
So in until the 2020s
there were experts
some experts in India and they called
themselves strategic affairs experts
right the word geopolitics did did not
register in the Indian vocabulary. So
all these experts they used to call
themselves strategic affairs experts.
Then I did this podcast with Reanir
Alabadia. It was probably in 2021
in which I discussed geopolitics and
then this word entered the Indian
lexicon geopolitics and now everybody
discusses geopolitics.
So now and now people have I think more
of an understanding of the wider world
out there because until the 2020s when
Indians thought of foreign policy,
international relations, all they
thought was Pakistan, Pakistan,
Pakistan, Pakistan. Then later China
came on the horizon, people Indians
started understanding that China is also
maybe a larger threat. And now Indians
can see much a much broader picture
and these days everybody speaks about
geopolitics on YouTube. News readers are
considered to be experts. So and and
Indians consume a lot of geopolitical
content. So everybody has opinions now.
And when you have an opinion, you
believe you're an expert. Well, I don't
think it's a bad thing. At least Indians
are now better informed. Maybe not
completely well informed or whatever but
it's a good thing overall that Indians
are now interested in international
relations, geopolitics, the national
interest, the the competing interests of
nations. I think it's a great thing.
Akil GK says some people say bananas and
coconuts in India came from Southeast
Asia. Do you agree? I don't know. I have
not looked into the origin of bananas
and coconuts and papayas and
strawberries and whatnot. I don't know.
Yeah. So I don't know. I have not looked
into the origin of bananas or coconuts.
I think coconuts are all over the place.
So what bananas?
So I don't agree or disagree right now
because I have not looked into the
matter.
Pratana says tin bronze versus arcenical
bronze. So bronze
bronze is this alloy. Bronze is an
alloy. That's an interesting point
you're raising there. Ah, are we talking
about the Arian tourism theory? Okay, so
bronze is an alloy. What's an alloy? An
alloy is the combination of two or more
metals. Okay, so you melt one metal, you
melt another metal, you mix them
together, maybe
maybe you don't mix them, but you beat
them. There are various ways of forming
alloys. Typically, you take two molten
metals and you mix them together. Um so
when it comes to bronze, bronze is an
alloy that is primarily copper plus
either arsenic or tin.
Now tin
shugai
Turkmanistan gandhar that region. So tin
was available in mines
in the outermost northwestern fringes of
historical baratwash
which is see when Shri Chingis Khan
decided to pursue Jalaludin and enter
India
the border between central Asia and
India was the iron gates of Sdan sdan
sugdana let's find out where that is
okay iron gate of So dana where is it
located?
Defile between bulk bulk and summer.
So do we have it on the map?
Not this. Not this.
This is somewhere in Mumbai. What are
they doing? Uh iron gate of SDA.
Do we have Okay, we have coordinates
here. Uh coordinates. So let's go to the
map and
and use these coordinates. Now let's
open the map. Okay.
Um where is map? Here is map. Now we put
in the coordinates.
Zoom into the place and look what we
find.
So this is the place. Okay. This used to
be the border between India and Central
Asia. It was all the way here when Sri
Chingghist Khan entered India. So
essentially the border of Tajakistan and
Turkmanistan was the border between
Bharatwar and Central Asia.
Now um thin
was found in Shortugai which is
Tajakistan, Turkmanistan somewhere there
also northwest Afghanistan etc. tin. So
bronze is maybe 90%
copper, 10% tin or something. So maybe
12% tin or something. And if you don't
have tin, then you can use arsenic,
which is a poisonous metal.
But you can use arsenic to make bronze,
the alloy with copper.
So before tin was discovered, bronze was
made with arsenic.
And you find arsenic bronze in
various parts of the world including
India including the Sarasati Synindu
region during that phase of India is it?
Let's see. Let's see. Let's see. Yeah, I
haven't really studied this in great
detail but it's a very interesting
topic. Arsenic bronze
in this
in this valley. Do we do we have this in
this valley?
prominent bronze blah blah blah blah
naturally it's a tin okay so we used
industriologist used arsenic and tin
with copper to achieve superior
barana arsenic was a dominant alloy with
count arsenic and tin were the key
yeah so I suppose that if you
if you could determine a create a
timeline of when arsenic gives way to
tin then it could indicate when
it could indicate certain aspects of the
chronology of
Indian industry. Yeah. So it's something
I have to look into in more detail but
it's a very interesting topic that
you've raised. So I will look into this
in more detail. Okay. Cavia chef says
most people in in Abrahamic religions
are not patriotic towards India.
Religion comes first. Mass conversion to
Christianity is happening all over like
building a Trojan horse in India. Will
India become Troy? Well, the way things
are going in maybe 50 years India will
yeah they will take over India. The
Abrahamic religions
see
Indian civilization,
Indian culture, Indian religion which is
various aspects of dharma. They have
always depended on state support.
always without state support,
polytheistic cultures die.
And today in India, you have a
government and a system that is
supposedly secular.
But secularism in India means
hindophobia.
India obviously is the most hindophobic
nation in the world. If you look at
various aspects of the Indian
constitution, various ways in and
policies that are you know various ways
in which policies are implemented and so
on, India is the most hindophobic nation
in the world. Hindus are second class
citizens already as per the constitution
and the laws and the policies of the
government of India.
Plus you have tremendous amounts of
money being poured into India and these
religious conversion activities,
conversion of people on an industrial
scale into into uh Abrahamic religions
so on. Um
yeah so it's it's very likely that
Hinduism will not really be there in the
22nd century.
And if you see I mean Indians are so
gullible,
Indians are so childlike.
If you look at if you visit large cities
in India, you will see Christmas
decorations all over the place. You will
see Hindus wishing Hindus a happy
Christmas, merry Christmas. You will see
Hindus dress as Santa Claus. I just
don't get what on earth they're trying
to do.
So Indians are deluded. Indians have
this death wish it looks like and which
is and the government doesn't care about
Indian culture clearly no
beyond slogans and token
developments like you know I'll not give
examples what's the point so yeah will
India become Troy it is a very
significant possibility that India will
go down the path of Europe what happened
to Europe a thousand years ago
could happen to India in this century.
It's just happening in front of us. How
many new temples are being built in your
city? How many new Hindu temples are
being built in your city or town? Now
compare that with religious structures
of the Abrahamic religions. How many new
of those are new such structures are
being built all across India? There's
hardly any new Hindu temples been being
built. But Abrahamic structures are
cropping up, mushrooming all over the
place, encircling ancient Hindu temples
and so on. It's a very well organized,
very well planned, organized
and executed
strategy
and it looks like the government of
India is is turning a blind eye or maybe
even participating. So yeah, looks like
we are the possibly the last few
generations of Hindus left in the in the
world. In the future, maybe our
descendants will talk about Hinduism
like they speak about Zoroastrianism or
maybe uh the religion of Babylon or
something, something of the past, the
Egyptian religion. Ah they used to be
polytheists. Fascinating. Okay. Uh Gpati
says in a capaci capacitor carrying AC
current no charge crosses the dialectric
how does Maxwell's fourth equation
explain this is the current passing
or is it a field effect I had an
electromagnetic course last year but
never understood look I will have to
brush up my electromagnetic theory to
answer your question I will have to draw
a diagram capacitor carrying AC
capacitor carrying AC
capacitor stores charge charge.
How can it carry AC current?
No charge crosses the diode. How does
is the current passing or is it a field
effect? Look, I have to brush up my
electromagnetics. Okay, this is all
[laughter]
stuff that I haven't looked into in
quite a while and I'm not sure
capacitors can carry AC current.
Capacitors can hold charge and then
discharge like that. And what are the
field effects and so I I'll have to I
can't answer right now. I'll have to
brush up my electromagnetics. I have
uh
I have uh the Sham book on that. I could
look into it, but yeah, this may not be
the right forum for that.
Lollipop says, "Oh, don't question."
Well, thank you very much, Lollipop.
Thank you.
Um Rajat says, "How matter occupies
space due to pi exclusion principle in
lay layman's terms?"
The poly exclusion principle. [laughter]
The power exclusion.
Okay.
The power exclusion principle says
that. So there are certain particles
called ferons.
They there are we know about the
subatomic particles electrons protons
neutrons bz you know w bzons and
whatever these are subatomic particles
these are classified into particles that
obey the bin statistics and the firmy
direct statistics particles that obey
the firmmy direct statistics are called
fermians particles that obey Bose
Einstein statistics are called bzons
particles that are firmians
they obey the pi exclusion principle
which says that um
no two identical firmians can occupy the
same energy state in a system. So if you
have an atom
an atom with a nucleus positively
charged nucleus which is protons and
neutrons bound together by nuclear glue
the strong uh nuclear force the so you
have a nucleus and then you have a cloud
of electrons
you know you could you could visualize
it as a you know electrons circling the
nucleus it's not like that but you can
visual visualize it like that. So the
the electrons
they are organized in energy levels
and no two identical
fermons
spin up spin down can can occupy the
same energy level which is why electrons
are spaced out and that's why we have
the shell configuration 1 s 2s spdf all
that stuff u so essentially it's like
you know you have an apartment building.
You have a high-rise building. You have
a ground floor, first floor, second
floor, third floor, that sort of thing.
In the ground floor,
you have rooms. In each room, only two
guys can sit, but not two identical
guys. One would spin up, one would spin
up, spin down, that sort of thing. And
uh
and electrons can occupy higher floors
only after they fill up the ground floor
and that sort of thing. So, because of
that, matter doesn't clump together
everything in one place. That's why
matter is spaced out and that's why
atoms occupy space. There is something
called pi
degeneracy pressure.
So there's there's a pressure if you if
you try to squeeze an atom the there's a
pressure that you will feel outwards
because of the power expansion principle
and that's why matter essentially
occupies space if it makes sense. Uh RTX
army thank you very much RTX army shared
it very much. Thank you. Brown
Leprechaun says, "What is hidden in the
Vatican City?" Roman wealth.
Well, uh I haven't been I haven't been
there, so can't say. And even if you uh
if you go to the Vatican City, they will
not let you see what's hidden there. So,
it's it's all secrets. They have a
secret library there. They have secret
vaults and god knows what else secret
stuff there. That's all secret. And the
definition of secret is that we don't
know. So I can't say what's hidden there
because it is all secret. They're very
secretive about what they've hidden
there. There's obviously a lot of stuff
that's hidden there. A lot of books that
you're not able to you're not allowed to
access. Maybe uh books with uh I don't
know some important information or maybe
knowledge that stolen from various parts
of the world or god knows what else.
Can't say because of secret we can't
say.
Swastik Mahesh says, "How can India help
the Balojasthan freedom movement?" I
would say that India can help the
Balojasthan freedom movement in a lot of
ways. By funding them through third
third parties, by providing them arms,
ammunition, training, munitions,
whatever, political support, diplomatic
support. There are so many ways that
India can do that if India wants to.
Right?
Oiler says Russia has always been bad to
its neighbors 1800 until now. invading
Ukraine even though Ukraine is sovereign
nation. Every right to join NATO look
into Russian atrocities. Okay sir, thank
you very much. Very bad. Russia very
naughty. Always very naughty. Always bad
things they do. Bad to its neighbors.
1800 till now.
Ukraine is a sovereign nation. Every
right to join NATO. Yes sir. Yes sir. Do
you know Russia also wanted to join
NATO?
Russia also wanted to join NATO.
If Russia had joined NATO, do you think
any of these things would have happened?
Do you think any of these issues would
have happened? Russia wanted to join
NATO before the formation of the Warso
pact. Let's fact check that. Okay.
Uh did Russia want to join NATO before
formation of Waro
block?
Yes,
the USSR formally proposed joining NATO
in 1954,
but the western powers rejected this
and that's why the next year the USSR
formed the Warso pact. The USSR wanted
to join the western block and live in
peace with everybody.
Did you know this? Russia very bad. West
very good.
Russia always bad.
Now let's let's let's do a followup to
this. Okay.
Did Putin
want Russia to join NATO?
Ex NATO head said says Putin wanted to
join alliance.
Putin wanted to join the alliance early
on in his rule.
Do you understand?
Even Vladimir Putin wanted to join NATO.
If Russia had been allowed to join NATO
during Vladimir during the early part of
Vlad Vladimir Putin's rule, do you think
the Ukraine war would have happened?
Please look at the big picture.
Don't fall prey to propaganda.
The USSR wanted to join NATO before the
formation of the Warso block.
The Western nations rejected the USSR's
proposal to join NATO. If the USSR had
been allowed into NATO, the whole world
would have been at peace.
But the West rejected that. The West
wanted to keep the USSR out and the West
wanted to disintegrate the USSR.
And Putin also once he came to power in
the early 20 late 19th c late 20th
century when did he come to power early
21st century whenever it was he also
wanted to Russia to join NATO the west
again rejected that please let's
study history a little bit then you will
see the bigger picture of what has
really happened and who's the real
villains out there. Uh Ishan Singh says
favorite bodybuilder Arnold Ron Coleman
somebody else
Arnold
I mean compared to today's bodybuilders
the mass monsters Arnold sometimes you
could say looks small right but Arnold
is the greatest Arnold Schwartzenega
I'll be back and Ronnie Coleman also
obviously Ronny Ronnie Coleman is let me
just quickly see Ronnie Coleman
lightweight baby is is that the
lightweight baby. Yeah, this is the guy,
right? But he's also one of the all-time
greats. I would say Arnold and Rooney
Coleman are two of the all-time greats.
And uh I have Arnold's book over here.
Used to be back here. It's now over
there. Arnold's encyclopedia of
bodybuilding.
Right.
Uh Commando says, "Worm holes and white
holes, do they exist?" Explain Einstein
field equation and its solutions. How
can I explain Einstein field equation?
[laughter]
Okay, first of all, do wormholes exist?
We have never
observed a vermma hole. We have never
observed a white hole, but some of the
objects we do observe may actually turn
out to be wormholes or white holes.
Wormholes
would also look from far away just like
black holes. They would also have many
of the properties that black holes have
and their effects on the surrounding
regions would be very very similar to
the effects that black holes have.
White holes could also sometimes mimic
black holes in some ways. Maybe quazars
could have white holes at the center. So
we don't know for sure. And there are
certain ways of testing that out also.
For example, if you have a wormhole,
okay, at the center maybe the super
massive black holes at the center of
galaxy centers of galaxy are wormhole
perhaps. Right? Some of these active
some of these galactic centers are
active galactic nuclei and there may be
ways of determining whether it's a black
hole or wormhole because if matter falls
into a wormhole throat there are certain
properties and then certain phenomena
that you could observe and so on. So we
don't we don't know for sure for certain
that wormholes have been existed have
been observed white holes have been
observed but they do exist as valid
solutions to Einstein's field equations.
Now I cannot explain Einstein's field
equations and solutions over here. Come
on that's that's a two over lecture at
least.
Um Pratik Shenoi says why do you add
Shri before Shri Chinghan is sarcasm? No
it's not sarcasm. I respect the guy
great man Shri Chingis Khan
Gapati says you mean Celt Celtic Dhi and
Patrick Brock I will neither confirm nor
deny
you seem to be a very observant person
sir but I shall [laughter]
well
these nasty chaps playing nasty games on
NX there are enough people who get
fooled by them
I commend your intellect sir but I shall
I maybe that answers your question but I
shall neither confirm nor deny but I
appreciate your intellect
appreciate it very much all right
M sack says I am seeing my colleagues
taking leave leaves for Xmas Christmas
over Diwali should Indian corporates
change the yearly leave renewal to
around October November you can't tell
corporates and private private companies
what to do they can formulate their own
rules
My question is why do we even have a
Christmas vacation in India? Our
holidays are during the Diwali period,
right?
We should have Diwali vacations. We
don't ideally in India we should not
have a summer vacation. We should have a
winter vacation 2 months official leave
for schools, colleges, universities,
etc. and whatever other institutions and
that leave should be in should be
centered around Diwali, not summer
holidays. See, India has summer
vacations. Why? Because India was under
British occupation and the British like
to take a couple of months off during
the summer and go to Shimla or Manali or
wherever.
And after we became supposedly
independent, we have slavishly blindly
continued the same policy that the
British had without understanding why
the British did that.
What's the point of having a vacation in
summer where you can't travel and you
can't go out, it's uncomfortable. You
should do this in winter and it should
be centered around Diwali. That is one
easy way to decolonize. But no, we are
slaves. We are sheep right in India.
India is so deeply deeply colonized. Do
you people don't even realize that?
Why do we need a Christmas vacation? Why
on earth do we need that?
If someone wants to take leave for
Christmas privately, they can take it.
You know, paid leave or unpaid leave or
whatever the hell that is. But the
official vacations in India should be in
winter during Diwali around that time
two months at that time that's the best
part best time in India to have a
vacation
K thank you very much Shravia K
appreciate it very much
okay
Sunu Lal says are you satisfied with
questions of history geopolitics asked
by viewers
Am I satisfied?
It doesn't matter whether I'm satisfied
or not. Are you all satisfied with uh
the answers? [laughter]
Look,
yeah, overall you get interesting
questions, especially when it comes to
history, I get interesting questions. So
when I do the live live stream like the
one I did yesterday in which I invite
questions in the comments I get some
really really interesting questions
every time and some people like for
example Amisha etc they ask so many
questions I cannot I I sometimes I'm
tempted just to take 20 of one person's
questions because the questions are
interesting sometimes so interesting but
I typically take like three four off of
one person's questions because otherwise
lots of people will complain I know
because I've been doing this for a long
But the point is people ask really
really interesting questions when it
comes to history. Now if I were to do a
similar live stream on geopolitics
based on questions asked in the
comments, I'm sure many of the questions
would be really interesting. So and I've
seen that u questions asked during in
the super chat are typically of a higher
quality than asked in the live chat. So
yeah,
Gapati says US air strikes over Nigeria
thoughts. Well, it is what it is. What
can what are my thoughts? The US will do
what it wants. The US will do it because
it can. Godliness says PM says a lot in
regards to dismantling colonialism but
his own government from past 11 years
has done did nothing for technology.
Technological sovereignty we stand
nowhere in chips. AI, biotech or quantum
computing.
Um technological sovereignty and
decolonization are different topics. Uh
but there is so much more. I agree with
you. There's so much so much more we can
do.
Uh now we have this semiconductor
mission and we are man beginning to
manufacture chips of certain uh certain
kinds of chips and also we are taking
baby steps. Uh we're going to start
somewhere. So we have started the
process in AI. I'm not sure what on
earth we are doing. I have no idea.
Biotech I'm not sure. Quantum computing
I don't know. See
to stand at a global level and to
compete at the global level in any
technology whether it's AI,
biotechnology, quantum computing
whatever you need a worldclass education
system and higher education in
universities and colleges that is that
is focused on research and development.
You will never have high quality
research
done in a country which has a rotten
education system.
If you if we want to compete with the US
and China in cutting edge technology,
we're going to have to revamp the entire
education system. And nothing like that
is being done.
It's I'm not asking for the luxury of
having a world-class education system.
It's not a luxury.
It is non-negotiable.
Without that, we will never have
technological sovereignty.
So,
so that's where we stand right now. What
about space exploration?
What's happening? So, yeah, there's a
lot that can be improved
when it comes to dismantling colonial
colonialism. So much should be done, but
well, I don't know, maybe it'll take
another hundred years. I don't know.
We'll see.
Mary Kane, good to see you, ma'am.
Working on it. I think there's a timeout
on this or longer question. More
test
limit for dollar $5. Okay.
Okay. All right. Good to see you, Mary.
Good to see you always. Uh Christian
Bordoy says, "You would be pleased to
know that the history books till class 7
have been corrected. My mom is a
teacher. The books of 8 9th 10th are
also corrected. I'm I'm glad. I'm glad.
Yeah.
So certain steps are being taken. See
Indians have been
demanding for 11 years please correct
the history textbook. So now something
is being done.
But what about the deeprooted problems
in the Indian education system? Right?
We need merit.
We need
quality teachers. We need a focus on
understanding,
not memoriz memorization.
We need to focus on critical thinking,
not root memorization.
There's so many fundamental issues that
are completely being ignored. So, I'm
glad that some textbooks have been
corrected, etc. Uh, but it's just baby
steps, but it's it's definitely good
steps nonetheless. So I'm glad the
scrummer says, "How did ancient
ctographers create fairly accurate maps
without having advanced technology?" I
am not really sure. I haven't looked
into this matter. How did ancient
ctographers uh create maps? I suppose I
I don't know. I've not looked into this.
Uh
this I suppose they would navigate
coastlines
and use their imagin. I'm not I'm not
sure. Look, I don't know about this.
Sorry. Uh fast snail says whom to
believe China or the US with respect to
Arunachal claim
what has the US said is the US also also
claiming Arunachal now
I'm not sure what the context of your
question is I believe the US national
security report or something has said
that China considers Arunachal Pradesh a
core issue or thing
and China does claim Arunachal Pradesh.
So I'm not sure there is a either or
situation here. The Americans kind of
have acknowledge that China claims
Arunachal Pradesh as one of its core
interests or issues and China does do
that. So yeah, it is what it is. Okay.
Uh Rajut says neuroscience can't define
consciousness and there are 300 theories
and none of these are even practical.
Science is only good for objects. How
can a physical brain with electrons,
protons, neutrons have first person
experience? Upanishad
there is no consensus. There is see I'll
tell you what is the central problem
with consciousness.
The central problem with consciousness
is that it first of all it exists.
When you see a cat you know look there's
a consciousness there. It's conscious.
We know that when you see a butterfly,
you know it's conscious in some shape or
form.
When you see a dog, you know it's
conscious. So when you see it, you
recognize it immediately. You see a
fish, you know, yeah, that thing is
conscious. There is a consciousness
inside. It may not be a higher
consciousness like ours, but it there is
a consciousness there. So when we see
it, we recognize it immediately, which
means it exists.
But now the question is how do we define
it? and we are unable to define it. So
it's it's something that does exist but
we are unable to define it
scientifically.
I am not talking about philosophical
definitions and so on. I'm talking about
hard science. From a hard science
perspective we are unable to define
consciousness. Let's say I create a
black box. It's a box. Okay. 1 2 3 4 5
6sided box. Cubicle box completely
black. I don't know what's inside. If
there's a consciousness inside that box,
how do I define it? What will be the
characteristics of that consciousness?
Can I define it from a physical
perspective, from a physics perspective,
from a quantum theory perspective, from
an information theory perspective, from
a neuroscience perspective, from various
perspectives? Can any of these
disciplines give me a rigorous
definition of consciousness? None of
these can.
Right? So that's why people talk about
upanishads and whatnot and whatn not but
that's not science that is philosophy.
Please understand there's a there's a
difference between philosophy and
science and when you are a scientist you
cannot start dabbling in 50 different
things. You have to be disciplined
enough to remain in the physical realm
which is observable objects,
quantifiable objects, measurable
objects, observable phenomena and so on.
The physical world only
And why is it important? Because
consciousness is attached to the
physical world. This thing here isn't
conscious. Right?
This [clears throat] thing here, this
lens cap isn't conscious. We know that.
But this here is conscious.
Consciousness is attached to the
physical to physical objects. That's why
there has to be ideally a physical
definition of consciousness. But we are
unable to do that. So that's the issue.
Yeah,
Pratt Dana says, "Wholesale transfer of
SSVC
syndi civilization harapan technology
post 2000 BC to Mediterranean region.
locals in Troy Crete were making indust
beads with the same style. Okay. Um
we know that around 2000 or 30,000 BC
people in cited
frescos of Indian monkeys langours.
Yeah. And I haven't looked into the lead
making in the region in the
Mediterranean region but it's very
interesting. I'll have to look into
this. So clearly if
they did frescos, they painted frescos
with Indian langors, clearly they had
connections with India and maybe Indians
even came and gave them gifts of
langors, right? Or maybe their traders
came to India and they saw these
fantastic monkeys and maybe they came
back to cit and then drew the drew the
langors. For example, see u let's take a
look at the look at the langu frescos.
Minoa
uh Minoan civilization
Santoini Santorini is it Creit
Santoini
Mino.
So there we have it. These blue monkeys
are actually Langors. Clearly Langor.
There we have it. Same guy.
[clears throat]
So how did this happen? So, Minoan
civilization was in Santorini, right?
Santorini.
Um, Crescent Shape Island. So, where is
it? Let's let's let's see the map. Yes.
It's not quite Creit.
It's it's near Cre, isn't it? Yeah. So,
this is Creit and north of Cre you have
Kira. Uh, Santorini. As you can see,
it's a volcanic caldera. there was a
gigantic volcanic eruption there which
ended the civilization there and so on.
So uh that's where you know they they
painted these frescos with Indian
langour. So clearly there was a
connection all these thousands of years
ago. Um so clearly ancient connections
existed
and I'll have to look into what you're
mentioning here but I would not be
surprised that this is obviously going
to be a fact. Yeah.
Uh Dana says December isn't 12th but
10th month
oto
8 9 10 Latin how do you say 8 9 10 in
Latin
in French it is
uh 1 to 10 1 to 10 in Latin
okay
September October December. So it's o
September, October, November, December,
which means the 7th month, 8th month,
9th month and 10th month. But December
is the 12th month. So what happened? So
you see the the European calendar was
very primitive. They probably had 10
months initially. Then
then Julius Caesar said, "I should have
a month named after me." So July was
inserted. Then Augustus said if my
adoptive father has a month named after
him I should also have a month named
after him. So after Julius July came
Augustus is August.
So earlier they had 10 months but two
extra months were added July and August.
So that's why the 10th month ended up
becom becoming the 12th month. That sort
of thing. Uh that's kind of roughly what
happened. The European calendar is very
primitive and they even even today it's
it's not very accurate. Yeah. you have
leap ears and all that stuff. All right.
Krishnant Bordoy says, "I have also seen
your video on wanting the government to
make Sanskrit the national language and
revamping the entire education system,
but to do that they need 362 seats.
I'm not sure if they will do it even if
they they have 400 seats. I'm not sure.
I hope I'm wrong.
Look,
362 seats are needed for what? For
a constitutional amendment is it or what
exactly is it? Maybe it's that how many
seats are needed for a how
many seats seats in parliament
are needed to pass a constitutional
amendment.
in uh
oh come on in Lok Sabha
um two/3 majority
okay yeah whatever that is
uh
yeah you need you need the will to do
I'm not sure if our politicians even
understand the importance of making
Sanskrit the national language and
there's a lot of resistance against uh
what what many people called the
imposition of Sanskrit Sanskritization
and all that. Yeah. So lots of issues.
Uh MK says is Christmas linked to Roman
sol invictus and Saturnelia how are they
similar to Sranti which marks the sun's
shift solid victus and harvest? Look I
don't know. I don't know the details. I
have not studied this.
I have a podcast with a professor with
with with Dr. CK Raju in which he may
have spoken about this or he may have
spoken about this in other videos.
But I haven't studied this in detail. I
haven't looked into this. I haven't
researched the specific
uh festivals that are linked with the
specific pagan festivals that were
appropriated by Christians and converted
into Christ into Christmas probably Sat
Satnelia
but I'm not sure exactly which one it is
and the connection with Sranti I'm sure
there must be some but I don't know the
specifics so can't say sir
okay Tech death says if pashtuds are of
Indian descent why are they genetic
outliers even among Indian Muslim
communities? Studies like whatever have
shown Iranian central Asian ancestor
with minimum south Asian administ from
Indians. Look at listen please pay
attention
pay attention please.
Gandhar has been under foreign
occupation for 1,000 years.
Fact number one, it is the first part of
India to fall to the Turk invasion
1,000 years ago.
Okay. So, the Pashons
are the descendants of the Indians of
that time who had to intermingle and
intermix with with foreigners.
Please be aware of this fact.
If you look at the population of
Afghanistan today, the majority ethnic
group is the Pashons.
But there are lots of Turk ethnic groups
like the Turkman's
uh the the Hazaras are Mongolic, the
Turkman's uh the Usbeks and whatnot
and they have been around for a thousand
years. So obviously that those genetics
will will introgress into the Pun
population because those Turk groups
were the hammans. They were the foreign
occupiers
who had subjugated the ancestors of the
people who are now known as the pashons.
Their ancestors were Hindus and
Buddhists.
So those genetics will enter the
population over a period of a thousand
years. No question about it. Look at the
the the the parses of India. They came
from Persia, right? 1,200 300 years ago.
They have lived peacefully in India for
1300 years.
They have not been oppressed. But still
their genetics show more Indian genetics
than Persian genetics. Even though India
Persia have very similar genetics but
you can see the differences. So then you
can ask the question that if if paris
Indians Eurostians are of Persian
descent why do they have more Indian
genetics than Persians? But you know the
answer right you know because they've
been living in India for 1300 years and
that amount of that long aer time is
going to have the effect of having the
local genetics introgress into your
populations. Similarly for the pashons
please understand it's not a population
that was isolated from the occupiers and
invaders for a thousand years. Doesn't
that explain everything?
Think.
Think. Please think
it's so frustrating when people don't
think
we for Valerox. [laughter]
Thank you sir. Thank you so much. Thank
you.
Pratik Pratik Shenoi says could India
realistically shift into a Hindu nation
of Hindu monarchy by dismantling
democratic structures like Islamist
groups influence Bangladesh into Islamic
state.
India realistic leadership by
dismantling democratic structures. Who
will do it?
Who will do it?
If you do it, you're going to have to do
it across the country.
This is a gigantic country. You do it in
one part of India, 78 other parts of
India will resist and protest. They will
say we don't accept this. Then what will
you do?
Unless you have somebody of the caliber
of Chhatrabat Shivaji Maharaj or
Rajendra Chola
or
or Kaneshka
or Chandra Gupta Moria with Vishnu Gupta
Chanaka somebody of that or or Lord Ram
or Lord Krishna somebody of that stature
and caliber will have to come and do it.
Mediocre politicians won't be able to
achieve any such thing. We really will
need at this point in time the return of
Lord Krishna like he had promised.
Nothing else will save India at this
point in time.
Krishant Bordaloy says Indian Jenzine
towns is are becoming more conservative
region reason I'm not sure.
Are Indian Jenzee kids becoming more
conservative?
I think um there is a revival of
interest in Indian culture these days.
There is a revival of pride in being
Indian which is kind of paradoxical
given the fact that we are so mentally
coronized and our education system
mentally coronizes us even further.
Maybe it's the influence of social
media. Maybe social media has a good
influence as well apart from whatever
else. Um so could be multiple reasons. I
haven't really looked into this. I
haven't thought about this but uh I hear
that Indian Jenzi is kind of becoming uh
more proud than previous generations
about being Indian and more into Indian
culture which I obviously welcome very
much. Rik says how did Bhakty Kilji meet
his death? There are multiple versions
of what happened. I'm not quite sure
what happened. Was he assassinated by by
one of his Turk rivals? Was he defeated
by the by the Tibetans and and slain
there? I'm not really sure what exactly
happened. There are different versions
of what happened. Uh yeah, Mary Kane
says,
"What if India 2026 to-do list?" Okay.
A what if
India 2026 to-do list? One, Moonbase
logistics hub build out to EML5
to protect logistics. Question, who will
protect India's digital security?
I would love to have a moonbased
logistic hub.
Yeah. Um
but for that India will have to first
reach the moon.
Right now we
have a dead lander on the moon which
landed successfully and also did a hop
experiment. So that was Chundrean 3. The
next Chandrean mission will probably be
a sample return mission. So I believe
ISRO has plans of sending humans to the
moon by 2040 or something mid 2030s
maybe 2040.
So that's going to way exceed the 2026
uh hope that some of us have. So 2026
won't be possible.
So the first landing will happen in 2040
and to build a logistics hubs hub and
all may take another 10 20 years. So
maybe in the second half of the 20th
centur 21st century India may have a
proper moon base with logistics hubs and
all that. Um
and obviously if you have a logistical
hub etc. you'll have to protect it. So
you may need some [laughter]
some um
some some military
presence on the moon which will be very
interesting which means other nations
will also have it. Uh who will protect
India's digital security is the
question.
Well who will do it? India will have to
do it. India's government will have to
do it. What do we mean by digital
security? It means our data security,
our data um our sovereign systems, all
of that needs to be secure.
It's the government's job to protect
India's, you know, critical vital data,
proprietary data and so on. So the
government is supposed to do it. I
suppose they are doing that.
And obviously there will be foreign
actors that will want to breach
the security and it's always a cat and
mouse game that's going on. So I hear
from let's say reliable sources that
India actually has a one of the best
cyber security defensive and offensive
uh capabilities in the world. India
doesn't for a change. India doesn't
boast about this. India stays quiet
about this but yeah we do have u pretty
good capabilities so that is reassuring
for meurva
Apurva adita ja says unknown gunman
having a good time I see well did
something happen did something happen
visav the unknown gunman I'm not aware
but okay
yeah I mean you do need unknown gunmen
especially in uh nations that are known
for terroristic activities and and
agendas. So yeah. Okay.
[clears throat]
Alzat. Okay. All right. Alzat says, "Can
we exploit Deoban and Belvi differences?
YKK I
when it comes to the various schools of
Islam, Islamic thought and all, I am no
expert in these things. I don't know
what are the differences between the
theis and the burelv and all. Theobandis
are the deoband is the alma mater of the
Taliban. Clearly the burelvi
school or whatever it is seminary is the
alma m of some else. Um I am not very
well informed about this. Yeah I'm no
expert in Islamic stuff so can't say. Uh
Mish Moes Sabrinat says why do almost
all countries including India have
decriminalized adultery in marriage? Is
this a sign of breaking societies down
by larger powers? Maybe.
So historically, how was it? If we read
the earth shastra,
was adultery punished? Probably it was
in some shape of or form. Not very harsh
punishments, but it was
definitely a punishable offense in some
way. I don't remember. Um, it's been a
while since I read the shastra and I
never looked into those those aspects. I
was more interested in the space
statecraft
and international [clears throat]
relations and such activity such such
such aspect of the earth shastra
but yes see today the entire world
follows the western systems and in the
west
well you know adultery is no big deal.
Adultery is it's not even regarded as a
sin or something evil or something
unacceptable anymore. It's just part for
the course. Most people marry for a few
years and then it's understood that
they'll give get divorced
and even while they are married they
have affairs and whatnot. So the western
system is the system that everybody else
has adopted including India. We have our
leaders have had this massive
inferiority complex. Everything the west
does we must emulate over here. And
obviously this is going to have a bad
effect on society.
And I would say look
I'm not sure it should be if it should
be criminalized but there should be a
strong taboo against adultery
and there should be
there should be social circumstances.
I'm not saying loss of life or or
violence or any such thing. I'm just
saying there should be some kind of
social circumstances that make adultery
something that nobody would want to do
because and a culture in which you have
adultery that that is rampant across
society is is a is a culture that's on
very shaky foundations because the
institution of marriage is one of the
major pillars of of civilized existence.
So yeah, in in the western world,
marriage is almost not really a very
strong organization or strong
institution anymore. So I'm not sure how
civilized you can be if you no longer
take marriage and the loyalty that comes
with it uh seriously.
Hyphen says medical in UK is so bad to
the point where we have to wait for
hours just to be seen in an emergency
and wait for weeks and months for a
surgery. Most people in the UK go to
India for treatment. Yes. It's become
they have engineered the the the
situation. It's the same in Canada. In
the US, if you have the money, you can
get things done quickly. If you have
insurance, you may have to wait and you
may have to stand in line and wait in
line and whatnot.
If you have if you are very wealthy, you
can skip the line. I suppose in the US
waiting for whatever lung transplant or
heart transplant or whatever. I suppose
if you have the money you could skip the
line. Um so yeah it's it's it's a world
in which the super rich don't have to
wait for hours or or any such thing but
ordinary people
they are better off visiting India you
know on medical tourism or whatever. So
the system used to be great in the past.
I mean if you look at Canada, so the UK,
Canada, the US, these are part of the
Anglosphere and you can see the same
pattern emerging across the Anglosphere.
So Canada has this free health care
system but now you have to wait for
weeks to get an X-ray for example
apparently in some parts of Canada. So
on so
this has been deliberately engineered.
There's no need for things to go things
to become this bad.
Um
yeah so it that's the quality of life
today that you have in the western world
in the UK the UK UK society is
disintegrating the UK's government is
what can I say yeah
sad sad indeed this is this is the
visible decline of the west that we have
that we are seeing here so yeah if you
if you can come to India we should visit
India maybe once in a couple of years if
you have any medical issues get those
get those fixed in India.
Bipol Singh says nothing against any
cast. Do you think that after obtaining
three consequent degree using
reservations still using it for becoming
a professor in top engineering college
stems the research op and quality of
teaching.
I
am a strong proponent of pure merit.
See there in any nation there's going to
be inequality and India was under
foreign occupation for thousand years.
So there's going to be tremendous
inequality. A number of people they
benefited from the foreign occupation
those who were collabor collaborators
and the rest of the people were
beggared.
Right?
So there's going to be this tremendous
inequality and and the British what they
did is they engineered all these
horrific problems in society and then
blamed it on the Indians. They imposed a
four-pronged cast system on India. They
made it official and then they blamed
the cast system for the evils that they
had introduced into the society. And
today this is what we are taught and we
believe that our ancestors were super
evil and blah blah blah. And that's why
we have reservations given to uh the
people who belong to the so-called lower
casts. I don't believe in this lower
upper cast at all. Okay? We're all
Indians. We're the same. We should not
have any of these things. But the
government mandates this, right? On your
school living certificate, your cast has
to be there. On your birth certificate,
your cast has to be there. The
government makes it mandatory for cast
to exist
and then they blame cast for everything.
You India has a cast system. Why don't
you erase cast? So my point is first of
all they have done they've created this.
The British created it and our
governments have perpetuated that. Then
they imposed reservations based on cost.
You know what reservations are not a bad
idea if they are applied if they are
implemented for maybe 20 years
and if reservations don't have the the
intended benefit in 20 years then
clearly the government has failed in
implementing reservations. It should not
take more than 20 years to rebalance
society if it's done right.
But reservations if they are to be given
they should be given on the basis of
your financial status financial
situation and circumstances of a family
not on the basis of cast. There are
plenty of people from the so-called
lower cast or whatever who are very
wealthy but they get the benefit of
reservations. Reservations if are if
they are to be given should be given
only on the basis of financial
circumstances.
If you are below poverty line yeah sure
give reservations but not forever.
So that's what I believe in. If we
continue reservations forever, it's
going to destroy Indian society and
everybody who is worth anything will
leave the country and and they will hate
India forever.
Yeah. So this is a recipe for disaster
reservations.
Kiran Moore says US leaked the document
of Putin talking to Bill Clinton about
that Pakistan should not have nuclear
weapons. Why is the US behaving so
immaturely?
Um, did the US leak it? Did somebody
else leak it? Is this a true document?
Is it a fake document? We don't know.
How do we know it's a it's it's genuine
document. And if it is a genuine
document, how do we know that the US
government has leaked it? Maybe somebody
who is no longer affiliated with the US
government may have leaked it. We don't
know for sure anything, right? We don't
know what is true, what is not.
So can't say for sure. There has been
this this report in the news that uh
there's been this leak
um
of this transcript or whatever of Putin
talking to Clinton about Pakistan. Let's
let's see what the news report says.
Okay. uh leaked Putin Clinton
uh conversation
about Pakistan
nuclear weapons.
Um
so this is coming out on what?
Facebook and YouTube
and also Times of India. Uh hunda with
nuclear weapons when Bosch and Putin
discussed declassified NSA documents.
Okay.
Declassified NSA documents
um documents made public this week.
Freedom of information lawsuit including
verbatim transcripts and so on.
Okay. So whatever it's not important for
the US. Yeah. Everyone knows Pakistan is
a terrorist regime. Everyone knows that.
And uh
Putin opposes Pakistan. Maybe they want
to ensure that Pakistan remains on their
side and doesn't go doesn't flirt with
Russia or something. Maybe there must be
some reason for it.
Uh Shatabhish says
same room two guys one still second
running. Both look at Andromeda same
time we'll see events days apart cause
special relativity between motion change
particip
because special relativity BT motion
change perception of time feels like
it's it doesn't it may feel like
it may feel like magic to you
but it's just physics.
Special relativity is actually
very simple compared to general
relativity.
If you just know basic calculus, you can
study special relativity. I'm not sure
if you need even need calculus, you
probably need some calculus. I mean, if
you take any book, any textbook on
modern physics, it's it's typically in
the first chapter.
So, if you know basic math, a little bit
of calculus, you can actually study
special relativity. There is no magic in
it. It may if you don't if you haven't
studied it then the effects will sound
will feel like magic time dilation
length contraction you know various
paradoxes like the grandfather paradox
and twin paradox and what is this
andromeda paradox sounds like magic it
may feel like you know it's a simulation
thing but it's just physics it's no
nothing special just physics
says could you and Sanjay Dakshit
arrange a debate with Duvarati and
expose him I no interest in debating
morons.
Okay, I've been I've been in in on this
do in you on YouTube for for a while
now, several years. Have you ever seen
me debate someone?
What is the point of me debating some
It will serve as entertainment for all
of you, I suppose. But what will I gain
from it? What will you gain from it
beyond entertainment? We all know the
guy has an agenda.
He clearly is on the payroll of of
whatever foreign powers. We all know it.
Then what? He's if you know it, he's
already exposed, right? If you know it,
he he is already exposed to you. I think
the whole country by now knows that he's
on the payroll of some foreign power. So
what is the point of me going on on some
live telecast or something with him and
exposing him? What's the point? Why
should I waste my valuable time talking
to that idiot?
What's the point?
All these debates, they have become a
form of entertainment. You have these
8:00 p.m. 9:00 p.m. debates on the news.
This this is just a form of
entertainment because these debates are
all shouting matches, people shouting at
each other, talking at each other.
But what is the outcome of the debate?
There is no outcome of the debate.
I just don't get what is the point of
these debate shows. I just don't get it.
A debate makes sense if there is some
kind of consensus that emerges as a
consequence. Or maybe it ends up
better informing the audience about
whatever is being debated.
It should be constructive.
It should have some constructive
outcome, a debate. Shouting at each
other, abusing and insulting each other.
What's the point? I don't I'm not
interested in that. I'm absolutely not
interested in that. So, I am not doing
any debates with anybody. Absolutely
not.
Monish says, "I'm 22 and I've seen and
read the world's na I've seen and read
the world's nature to a great extent.
All thanks to you." Very, you're very
welcome. Uh I can only show you some
some part of it of course. Uh but I lost
happiness in the process. [laughter] I
can't even share these things with close
ones. What to do? That's part of the
process of growing up.
You know when you were a kid, when
you're when you were a child, the world
is so beautiful. Why do we all remember?
Why do most of us who had
reasonably normal childhoods why do most
of us think of childhood as this
beautiful time of our life? is the best
time of our life. It's because the world
was so beautiful from our perspective at
the time. We had so little information,
so little knowledge. We were so
innocent.
Innocence is the lack of knowledge, lack
of understanding. So we thought
everything is just flowers and
butterflies and green grass. Everyone is
nice, smiles, happiness, all that stuff.
But as we start growing, we start seeing
things that we did not see earlier. And
that beautiful picture of the world
slowly gradually over time starts
crumbling. And then we feel that we have
lost our innocence. We've lost our
happiness. The world has changed. It's
not changed.
It has always been this way. But your
perception has changed. Your
understanding has changed. You have
started seeing things you did not see
before.
Yeah. You will not be that happy
anymore. [laughter]
It's just part of the process of growing
up.
And yeah, you will if you are
intelligent. See, the people who watch
this channel are obviously
higher in intelligence than the median
population of the world, right? So, if
you're intelligent, you're going to make
connections in your mind that others
won't be able to make.
But then if you try to explain it to
somebody, they'll say, "You are crazy.
You are crazy. You are a conspiracy
theorist. That's what they will say. So
you can't share these things with your
close ones. What to do? Nothing.
Nothing. What to do? You don't want to
share it with others. You know it.
That's good enough. And if it is
something if that knowledge is something
that you can use to make your life
better
either person in at a personal level or
a professional level or whatever then
then use it.
Knowledge is not always useful.
But if you know how to use it, it can be
valuable. So find ways of using it in
personal business life, professional
life, whatever. And that's what you can
do with the knowledge. So if you
understand geopolitics well, if you
understand all the nasty things that are
happening in the world behind closed
doors, if you can see the connections
and if you are for example a business
person or a trader, if you're trading
various commodities, you can use that
information significantly to your
advantage and make profits out of it. If
you can if you can foresee what's
coming, if you can if you can read the
trends and so on. So that's what you do
with it, right? Don't be upset that
you've lost your happiness. It's just
the process of growing up. You will
always be happier at the age of five
than you're at the age of 10. You will
always be happier at the age of 10 than
you at the age of 17.
And you will always be happier at the
age of 17 than you than you at the age
of 25. By the time you're 40, the world
maybe you you kind of get re reconciled
to the fact that the world is not what
it seemed by the time you're in your
40s, but that's just the process of
growing up and living life. Everybody
goes through this. If you still are just
as happy as in your 30s or in your 20s
as you were when you were 12, then
probably there's something wrong with
you. All right? So, don't be upset, sir.
Or don't be upset. Okay. Mach says, M
Modi Moodi Modi G tweet on Christmas. Um
yeah and Diwali. Yeah. Yes sir. That is
indeed true.
I agree. Yes sir.
All right.
Han Mo is say what are the Epstein files
and why they public publicize it?
Epstein files are
what are the Epstein files? U documents
related to the activities of Jeffrey
Epstein who apparently was some kind of
uh enabler of very evil rich people who
indulged in criminal activities in
involving underage people, [snorts]
persons, uh pedophilia and God knows
what kind of horrific stuff. And Epstein
was perhaps the middleman along with his
uh alleged uh
partner Julan Maxwell
and Epstein allegedly killed himself
perhaps possibly who knows and the files
are I don't know transcripts and logs
flight logs and photographs and god
knows what else related to his life and
activities and so on. Why have they been
publicized? Because the government has
had that for a very long time. It
contains the names of all the powerful
people who have done very nasty, very
evil stuff.
And if the people know that this exists
and if you don't publicize it then it
looks like you are involved in that the
government whoever is running the
government. So that's why it was
publicized but a lot of that is redacted
apparently and not even properly. So
yeah Ajay Sharma says after my Baltic
visit I saw elderly begging every 100
meters. Many say the life in the USSR
was better on housing, food security
where USSR failure narrative is a hoax.
Look, yes and no. The USSR failed as an
empire.
But they were able to give their people
reasonable amount of uh you know
security. Uh there were no famines.
Everybody had housing, guaranteed
housing. They didn't have to pay for the
housing. Everybody was guaranteed a
certain amount of food. You never
starved. You didn't have great luxury or
whatever, but you got the food on time.
You never had to beg for food or
whatever. Nobody begged. So those things
were taken care of. So clearly that is
true.
After the USSR disintegrated, you had
poverty, massive poverty in Russia until
Putin started fixing it. Then that that
took that process took time. But now
things are way better than what you had
during Yeltson's time. My goodness, what
Yeltson
also. So that that is true. But the USSR
did fail as an empire. They allowed
themselves to be encircled by the west.
They allowed their standards to to drop
and degrade. They allowed corruption to
permeate their life in a way that was
detrimental to the empire. Not like the
US which actually uses corruption to as
as as something that strengthens it
potentially. So yeah, the failure
narratives are true, but what you what
the people who lived in the USSR say
that you do not have any of these
problems during during the days of the
USSR, that is also true. So yeah, it's
it it's both ways.
Godliness says rapidly rising Muslim.
Okay, listen, I don't talk about
religious issues and all that,
especially when it comes to Islam. I
don't talk about it. It's just a policy.
So yeah, I am not discussing this. All
right. Um sorry about that but it's some
see I can't fight every every fight
every war so I don't I don't discuss uh
uh this specific matter
um makan says Hindus keep fighting
within themselves I have given up no you
don't give up you never give up until
death all defeat is psychological you
don't give up you never give up please
don't
okay Sabrinat says how to have a thick
skin from haters in our lives.
I don't know how to have a thick skin. I
suppose you are either naturally born
with it or you somehow develop it.
I am
kind of a public figure to some extent.
I
read the comments every week to look for
questions, ask questions and I see a lot
of comments that are very not very nice.
Does it affect me? [laughter]
It doesn't affect me at all. I think uh
the people I mean a lot of a lot of
people have given up being nasty in the
comments because it doesn't affect me.
See when somebody is being nasty to you
they want to achieve something. They
want to either demoralize you or to hurt
you very badly.
And if it doesn't have the effect then
they give up eventually.
Yeah. Uh so I I suppose me personally I
just have a naturally thick skin. I
don't I don't care what anyone says. I
don't care about anyone's opinion. I
know who I am. I know what I am. What
others say or think doesn't matter in
the least to me. And that's something
that just came with the package. I was
just born this way. But how to develop a
thick skin? Well, you have to convince
yourself that you know the opinions of
others don't matter.
See, you're going to live a certain
number of years. We don't know how long.
Maybe 100 years, maybe whatever the
number is. The gods have decided that we
we have nothing to do with that. You're
going to live x number of years.
See in your life people will come and
people will go. That is the the reality
of life. There's only one person who
will stay with you. Who's that? It's
you. So who's the most important person
in your life? It's you. So what should
matter to you? You should matter to you
and your opinion should matter. Why
should the opinions of others matter? So
you have to I suppose
I suppose logically think about it and
convince yourself in whatever way is
best that you know
let haters hate. Who cares? How do they
matter?
What matters is what you do with your
life. Focus on that.
Figure out what is important for you
from your perspective and and focus on
that. Work on that to help with
everybody else. That's what you should
do.
Godliness says, "I know people wait for
3 years for basic basic surgery in our
own government hospitals. We don't even
have proper doctors in our government
hospitals, but yeah, laughing on Europe
and the US is more patriotic for some
who's laughing.
Every nation has problems
in India.
I don't know about government hospitals
but in India if you can spend a little
bit of money you can get most things
done on demand.
If you have broken let's say a bone
somewhere you can get an X-ray in 20
minutes. I don't think you need to wait
for 3 months or 3 years for an X-ray in
India. And an X-ray doesn't cost
anything like what it costs in the US.
See, when somebody points out what the
what the situation is like in the UK,
I'm not sure if I am laughing at that.
I'm not showing I'm I'm I'm comparing.
But if you were to compare, the
situation in India is much better.
Things cost way less
and things get done fast.
There is no question about it. It's not
about being patriotic. It's about being
uh factual, I suppose. So, I'm not sure
why you're upset, sir,
and not trying to pretend to be
patriotic or whatever. When there are
issues in India, I'm the first to speak
about those things.
I'm not sure why you're upset.
Okay. Um,
Pratik Vor says, "Is Tamil Nadu India's
Japan in terms of preserving culture
while also developing at a rapid pace?
Shouldn't other states also learn from
Tamil Nadu? I don't I'm not very aware
of the situation in Tamil Nadu. How much
of our culture is being preserved in
Tamil Nadu? I'm not very sure about what
the actual situation is. So I'm not sure
I'll be able to answer this question.
Swastik Mahesh says, if given a choice,
which problem of India would you focus
on solving first? Secondly, how long can
PM Modi stay in power? Who can be a
successor?
uh if given a choice which problem of
India would I focus on solving first the
education system people [clears throat]
just don't understand how important this
is
I would focus on the education system
first and foremost I would fix that
it'll take at least 20 years if if I
start today but I know what has to be
done so yeah if given a choice I would
fix the education system
secondly how long can PM Modi stay in
power and who can be a success as long
as he's he's healthy and strong and
mentally fine He can stay in power I
suppose. Who can be a successor? I
suppose there can there are multiple
candidates or or or or [snorts] yeah
candidates
who could be picked from
um who could it be? Well, time will tell
I suppose.
Uh Narendrai says why are people in
India so discouraging? Um people in
India have become very negative over the
past 10,000 years. Yeah, they've
developed this crab mentality. If
somebody tries to if if somebody is
striving to do better in life, they'll
try and pull the person down. Uh I'm not
sure all Indians are like this. Many
Indians are very positive. But overall
over the past 1,000 years, Indians have
become pretty negative and pessimistic.
So it is something we need to be aware
of and we need to consciously try and
change this attitude. All of us.
Sahaj Dang. Sahaj Dang says, "What would
it realistically take for the Indian
government to replace wrote learning and
illogical homework with within with an
education system built around
creativity, critical thinking and real
world skills.
So what would it take? It has to be
deployed in phases. The reforms should
start
at the ground level which is nursery.
Start the reforms the nursery level
first year.
Second year
take that to junior kg. Third year take
it to senior kg. Fourth year take it to
the first standard. It will take 20 25
years to implement the reforms and what
reforms to be implemented. Look that
will take me two hours to explain but
I'll tell you where you can find uh what
I have recommended in in very great
detail. Let me give you very quickly
what it is. So what we shall do is we
shall go to my channel.
Okay. Um if you go to my channel there
is the live tab on that you go to the
oldest ones then you go down
and if you go to episodes 28
30 and 31 of Askabit I have given all
the I have listed down all the problems
and given all the solutions.
episode 28, 30 and 31 of Ask Abijit.
So if you want the answers, check these
episodes out. All right.
Okay.
Um All right. Next question.
Raj Rajat says, "Putting black boxes and
finding consciousness." Upanishad says
that the error you are making, you put
black boxes in your own consciousness
and thinking where it is. Upanishad is
asking when did you leave your
consciousness? Okay sir,
I think you did not um
all right.
Suga says which is the best country for
Indian passport bros Google it as don't
want to marry in India and Indian girl
because then Indian laws will applicable
which not only are biased towards women
but completely against men. I don't know
which is the best country for Indian
passport bros. Um
I think that is something you will have
to do your own due diligence and your
own research. Yeah. I can't make
recommendations that you should follow.
You this is if you want to go and settle
in some other country and marry a girl
from that country because you're scared
of whatever then you have to do your own
research and your own duty diligence. If
I recommend something and something
something bad happens to you, you got to
come and blame me then. So please do
your own research. Take your time. Do
your own due diligence.
Figure out figure it out for yourself
which is the best country from your
perspective and where you will find the
best girl of your dreams. All right. All
the best sir Suga. All the best. Omnik
says is there any possibility for Europe
and Japan getting free from the
stranglehood strangle hold of the US in
the upcoming times or is it already game
over for them? Most likely game over for
them. I don't see any possibility of
Europe or Japan getting free from the
strangle hold. I don't see that
happening anytime soon.
Danush says, "What can and can't be said
about the resurrection of Jesus based on
the evidence asking because many in the
west have claimed there is evidence for
this. I don't know of any such evidence.
I don't believe in magic. That's only my
bias. Of course, I may be completely
wrong and maybe magic is all over the
place. Then maybe these things happen.
But um I am not aware of any evidence of
whatever this is. Right? That's all I
can say. That's all I can say. I I I am
no expert in this religion. Uh the only
time I read something about this
religion is when I was probably 8 years
old one day stuck in a hotel room in a
euro in a city in Europe. And since I
was stuck in a hotel room and didn't
feel like watching TV, I I opened a
drawer and found a pocket Bible and I
read the whole damn thing. That's the
only time I researched this religion in
any any detail. And that was a long time
ago. And it did not have the effect it
was supposed to have, which was to
convert me to the religion. Didn't work.
So it did say something about
resurrection and so on, but
I have not found any evidence
personally.
Maybe you need to have faith to to to
see the evidence. Maybe I don't have the
faith. Maybe I'm faithless.
Right. Okay. Gapati says when Krishna
Gita says
the bat in his context is India. Every
translation says bat is Arjun attempt to
separate Hinduism and India. Yeah.
I don't know. I I personally am not
sure.
Which is the correct interpretation?
Even I used to believe that when he says
bata it means India but maybe he says
bata not bharata. I'm not sure. Uh so
yeah that's something I will have to
look into and then only I can answer it.
Right now I have not looked into it even
I am not sure which is the correct
interpretation. Uh so is this an attempt
to separate Hinduism in India? I am not
sure about that too. First of all, I'll
have to look into the translation and
understand and figure out which is the
correct interpretation and then I can
answer the question. At this point, I
can't. Rajat says, "In case you are
interested, I can can I send you Adwit
Vant lecture? You will yourself find why
it gives the best definition. Where can
I No, no, no, no, no, no. I don't have
the time to read to to to watch
lectures.
See, there's a reason why I don't watch
podcasts. I don't watch long YouTube
videos. I hardly ever watch movies. I
don't have the time. I have so much work
to do. I have these projects I'm working
on. I don't have time.
I wish I was in that position where I
could say please send me the lecture.
I'll watch it. I'll watch it a couple of
times. I understand. I don't have the
time. When I was a teenager, I had that
sort of time. When I was in my Yeah.
When I was a teenager, I had that sort
of time. Today, I don't.
Uh so yeah, please don't send it to me.
I know what Advent is. I know where to
find the lectures under with the
vidanta. I know where to find the
playlists. A swami servy I suppose or
somebody else. I can find all the
information if I need to.
I am very good at digging out the most
obscure of information.
Right? But I don't have the time to look
into this right now. And I know from
what perspective I want to study the
mystery of consciousness. Maybe I have
some understanding of my own.
Perhaps you should consider the
possibility that I may have some
understanding
that I have acquired over my lengthy
years on the planet. Maybe I'm not a
beginner. Perhaps perhaps you should
consider the possibility that maybe I'm
not a beginner in this matter. All
right. But I really appreciate uh
your offer of sending this lecture. I
simply don't have the time. So thank you
so much. It's it's very kind of you to
to want to do this
but I won't be able to watch it at this
time. When the time comes for me to
watch this I'll know exactly where to
find this stuff. So thank you so much
Ajat appreciate it. Sah says any plans
for a studio tour
one. Any plans for studio tour? What's
the point of a studio tour? You want to
see my studio? It's a mess. This part I
show it's nice. The rest is mess. It's a
working guy studio.
It's it's high entropy. The entropy is
high. Books, cables, stuff, equipment.
[laughter]
You I don't think you will gain any
value from that. Okay. It's high
entropy.
Uh what languages do I speak? I speak
four languages. Among the foreign
languages, it's English and French.
Yeah,
that's about it. All right.
Uh, Sager says, "How to manage time
effectively for maximum productivity.
Love you, sir." Old 2020 subscriber.
2020 subscriber. So good to have you,
sir. Thank you so much.
One of my first subscribers.
Thank you so much for being a longtime
subscriber. Yeah, this channel is what
it is only because of all of you
especially my earliest subscribers are
the greatest of greatest ones. Uh thank
you so much. Yeah. Uh how to manage time
effectively?
See there are some principles you have
to be clear about. First of all,
being busy is not being productive.
Secondly,
having a like 20 tasks to do in one day
is stupidity.
You should have maybe two or three tasks
to do in one day
as much as possible. All the all the
donkey work delegate to somebody else.
Okay? You should not have more than
three three big tasks in a day.
And just because you're busy, you're
doing this, you're doing that, you're
doing this, it doesn't mean you're being
productive. You're just being busy. But
maybe it's not moving you forward in
whatever you want to achieve in life. So
how to manage time effectively? First of
all, know your goals. Know your big
goals, 10 year goal. Know your one-ear
goal. Know your three month goal,
quarterly goal. And know your goal for
this week.
Maybe it will take only two or three big
tasks that will achieve your goal for
this week. Ignore everything else.
Ignore everything else ruthlessly.
And manage [clears throat] your energy.
Sleep 8 hours. Eat clean food. Exercise
regularly,
okay? And don't overwork. Working 12
hours a day is madness. Don't work more
than 8 or 10 hours a day. Sleep well and
keep your mind of things and that sort
of thing. It's very important to manage
your energy. Energy is very important.
If you are low energy, what will you
get? What will you achieve in life? You
have to be high energy. You need to have
that that fortitude within you. So
that's what you do. But the most
important thing is don't have too many
things to do on your plate in one day.
Always ruthlessly cut everything out.
Just focus on the two or three main
things and ignore everything else. Say
no to everything else. There'll be all
kinds of demands on your time and
attention. Ignore those and cut those
out. So if you're ruthless, if you
prioritize what is to be prioritized, if
you manage your energy well, if you know
exactly what's your long what your
long-term goals are, you'll be able to
manage time effectively. Everybody has
the same time amount of time in life. 24
hours.
So yeah, it depends on what you're
trying to achieve and so on. So the
these are the basic principles for time
management. James, my good old friend
James is here. Cobble is so beautiful.
Why doesn't the fourth largest economy
capture it? We being the 55th or even
worse in 1700s could
uh do we need to capture Kabul at this
point in time? We don't need to. We have
friends in Kabul.
Why do we need to capture Kabul? Look, I
can visit Kabul tomorrow morning if I
want to. And I I'll tell you what, I
will
get a pretty warm welcome in Kabul if I
go there tomorrow morning or next week.
I can assure you of that. We have
friends in Kabul.
And yeah, so we don't need to capture
Kabul. Kabul is beautiful. Ancient
Capisa, right?
Yeah.
So um
we see if the fourth largest economy
soon to be the third largest economy
eventually to be the largest economy. Uh
if we want it we don't need to capture
it.
See the U US it has access to the entire
world without capturing the entire
world. That's the right way to do
things. If an American citizen wants to
travel to let's say uh Romania tomorrow
morning, do they need a visa? They
don't. If they want to set up a business
in Romania, do you think they have they
have to face hurdles, obstacles? No,
they don't. Let's say they want to go to
uh Madagascar, no visa required, I
suppose. If they want to go to Rwanda or
whatever, isn't so what you need to
have. You need to be in a situation
where you don't have to capture a nation
but the doors of the nation be open to
you. So that's what India needs to
achieve and Kabul is indeed beautiful
and I assure you that Indians have a
warm welcome in Kabul.
Yeah. So we are on the right track.
King Ritwick says you remember do you
remember me class 10 student gave debate
on Mr. Gandhi. Yeah. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Uh yeah, you you g you did a debate on
Mr. Gandhi based on my videos. Then
principal your principal called your
parents. But your parents are as
intelligent as me. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Both are doctors. Your mom is a
neurosurgeon. Your mom explained to the
principal that she herself taught me all
these and I'm absolutely correct. Well,
that's fantastic. I'm so happy for you,
sir. Then she said to principal not to
disturb her on this small matters as she
has p patience to see in OT and ICU. Uh
principal sir then apologized.
[laughter]
You sir are a genius. Uh my teachers in
school depend on my parents as they see
them for free and they have also given
them free medicines. I know teachers
can't harm me. Well well
that's why I got the courage to speak
about it in school because I knew
nothing what will happen to me. Do you
think this type of type of influence
matters?
Also my mama also my my mom has
subscribed only two channels for me.
It's me and Nish Rajput. She also
watches your channel sometimes. I stay
away from Mr. Rati Type. Well, first of
all, I salute your mom and your parents.
Please give my regards to you and and
and my respect to your mother. That's a
great mom you have. Uh does this type of
influence matter? Certainly uh there is
no harm in having influence.
If you have influence, if you have
parents who are influential, why should
you be unhappy about that? Whatever
advantages the gods have given you in
life, make the best use of that. like
your mom is clearly a most intelligent
lady and uh yeah so I'm I'm so glad that
things turned out really well for you
and looks like your your principal you
know teachers are not going to stand in
your way anymore or or you know do
anything to hurt you or harm you. So
great job. I and and and you did this
uh but possibly not knowing what could
happen but yeah it it all turned out
very well. So congratulations the thing
things turned out very well. I I truly
commend the actions of your mom and yeah
keep having a positive attitude. Keep
learning. Keep st keep raising your
standards and yeah you are showing some
leadership qualities some independent
thinking
keep keep doing that stay on the track
and do well sir and I look forward to
hearing more from you in the future. All
right sir all the best do well do well.
Awesome.
Okay G namaste good evening. Recently
19-year-old Dvat Mahesh Reiki flawlessly
recited 2,000 complex Vic mantras in
even complex dandr
pattern. Why is this being referred to
as one of the greatest memory feats in
India? I am not aware of the details. I
obviously saw the news. Prime Minister
Modi also tweeted about this apparently
if I remember correctly. What exactly is
this feat? What is the dandruff pattern?
I am not aware of that. I have not
looked into it.
But uh a Vic mantra is typically one
shloka or one mantra and if you have
memorized 2,000 of those,
well that is an incredible achievement.
So let's quickly take a look at what the
news has to say about um
what what news we have about Dave
D.
Vat Mahesh Mahesh Reik so a 19-year-old
Vic prodigy from Maharashtra who
recently achieved fame for completing
the extremely difficult dandak
parayam of the Shukla yajurveda in Kashi
over 50 uninterrupted days in late 2025
a feat last accomplished centuries ago
showcasing incredible memory discipline
dedication he recited nearly 2,000
mantras using complex forward backward
patterns
earning him a accolades and recognition
from figures like Prime Minister Modi.
So the method is recited 2,000 mantras
roughly in in intricate complex patterns
forward backward etc daily for 50 days
rare feet first in 200 years
demonstrating exceptional Vic mastery.
The danda karma involves reciting
mantras in highly complex sequences
requiring extreme focus, incredible
memory, breath control and
synchronization. Not just wrote
memorization.
It's a tradition preserved by dedicated
scholars in Reiki's accomplishment
revived this ancient practice. Okay.
Clearly a most difficult feat
unprecedented in over two centuries. So
yeah, it's it's it's not just wrote
memorization. It it requires so much
more than root memorization. So clearly
a person of the utmost intelligence
and tremendous willpower, dedication, so
much more. So yeah, see India was was
always the land of scholars and and
people who
did inc incredible intellectual feats
and dabat mahesh clearly is uh carrying
that that torch forward the flame of
that ancient tradition forward. So, I'm
glad that he's doing that and hopefully
he will inspire more people to continue
our traditions and keep the traditions
alive and and achieve some of these
great incredible feats, right? Um, so
yeah,
great great accomplishment and he's a
young person just 19 years old. So, I
wonder what else he will accomplish in
life. I look forward to see what other
great feats he accomplishes. I'm sure
he's going to do much more. um much more
in life and things which are even
greater than what he has done thus far.
UMXG lol haha says VVS isn't here today
and the quality of the questions have
gone down I can I contribute to it as
well. Okay VSVS we haven't seen today.
Well we miss you VSVS and we look
forward to seeing you the next time.
Godliness says for my last question in
government hospitals I was not poking
you were being upset. Okay. Okay. Uh it
was it was just a general statement. I
hope we can differ on some topics. Of
course, we can differ on some topics. Of
course, we can. So, you were not poking
or being upset.
Uh you were making a general commentary
and yeah, there are people in India who
also who yeah
who have that attitude of of you know
trying to always paint India as better
than the west and laughing at the west
and all. So, yeah, makes sense based on
that perspective what you were saying.
And of course, we can differ. You don't
have to agree with me on everything.
Okay? If you agree with me on
everything, maybe there's something
wrong with you. You should be skeptical.
You should
have different perspectives, different
viewpoints. If I say something, you
should analyze it from different
perspectives. If you perhaps disagree
with it and you should try and find the
deficiencies and flaws that may or may
not exist in what I am presenting and
maybe try and improve upon what I'm
saying and maybe then you can put that
forth. So that's how you have a
constructive discussion, constructive
debate. That's how you can do it without
having a debate too. If a person is
saying something and you have some
doubts about it, you should do your own
research, due diligence so on. So it's
perfectly
good.
It's actually desirable to have
differences but in a constructive
manner. So all right. Oh, thank you for
clarifying that. And I wasn't really
upset. It's yeah it's all part of the
course. All right. Thank you. Uh Suga
says if I may ask what's your
qualification?
What qualification?
What my degrees? How how
I went through the education system and
I acquired some degrees a long long time
ago. How does it matter
if let's say I am illiterate. I did not
even do the 10th standard whatever does
it matter
how do you care what somebody's
qualification is
it doesn't matter what my qualification
is I don't care what degree I have or
what degree you have I only care about
the quality of your arguments the
quality of the information the quality
of the discussion that I can have with
you
So
uh qualifications don't matter.
Qualifications may matter when you are
in the initial phase of your adulthood.
When the job market demands
qualifications
when your 30s, 40s and when you at the
end of the day your qualifications don't
matter. What you accomplish in your life
matters.
Nobody cares eventually what marks you
got or what degree you have. own the
only thing is that matters is what have
you contributed to society. Please look
at life in that way and you will be
happier that way. Um
Ms. Gaming says why free pronunciation
sounds like Hindi his of French
pronunciation does it sound like Hindi?
Absolutely not.
No.
The French pronunciation is extremely
different from Hindi. Tremendously
different from Hindi. Would you like to
see how it sounds? Okay. Um,
French text.
Uh, whatever. French French
text.
Okay. Uh,
one second. Okay. Janev.
Okay. Let's open a Swiss newspaper.
Okay.
Um,
okay. accept.
Okay, let's read this one. Okay, then
tell me if it sounds like Hindi.
economic politic.
Cesar.
relative.
So tell me, does that sound like Hindi?
That's what French sounds like.
Does it sound like Hindi? It doesn't
sound like Hindi. Okay. The UMX uh once
again says is learning a new language
worth it or not?
Well, you need to have a reason for
learning a new language. Maybe you you
want to travel the world and maybe you
want to learn or maybe you want to
travel to let's say Italy and maybe you
want to spend 6 months in Italy. In that
case, it makes sense to learn basic
Italian. Maybe you want to study in
Germany then it makes sense to study
German. Maybe um you love French culture
then it makes sense to learn French.
So
that that is an actual reason for
learning a language.
But sometimes it makes sense to learn a
language just to to to
benefit from
the neuroplasticity.
It it generates new brain. So
neuroplasticity what is the definition
of neuroplastic? The creation of new
neural pathways right in the brain. So
there are various ways of of achieving
neuroplasticity.
One one way of doing that is to learn
how to write with with your non-dominant
hand.
Let's say most people are right-handed.
Try and spend 5 minutes every day
writing with your left hand. It will be
very awkward and weird, but after a
couple of weeks, you'll be pretty good
at it. Or let's say you are you you like
playing cricket. Learn how to bat with
your non-dominant hand. Learn how to
bowl with your non non-dominant hand.
That will create neuroplasticity.
Similar benefits will be achieved by
learning a new language. So, it keeps
your brain more agile. It it it it
probably increases your intelligence and
and it gives you different perspectives
because uh languages
they they they
have certain patterns that they etch in
your brain and different languages look
at the world in different ways. So yeah,
it's it's definitely worth it if you
have the f if you can find the time to
do that. Um, Riser says, "Why committee
of 300 PDF is on CIA? It's 300 control
the world." I don't know about the
committee of 300. I've kind of vaguely
heard about it, but I don't know exactly
what it is. I have not read it. I've not
studied it. So, I can't answer the
question. I'm so sorry. I don't know
what it is. I could open the PDF now if
it's available on Google. I'm sure it
is. And then read it, but that will
waste your time. So, maybe I'll read it
when I can find some time and maybe you
can revisit the question in the future.
Rej says why does some of the basic
concepts of quantum mechanics and
relativity not taught in schools
to inculcate curiosity and interest in
students?
I don't know. Look, quantum mechanics,
it cannot be taught at the school level.
I mean, yeah, you can teach some of the
mysterious phenomena associated with
quantum mechanics to generate curiosity.
Clearly, you know, the grandfather
paradox, the twin paradox, that's that's
that's special relativity, quantum
mechanics, the the the double split,
double slit experiment, that is
fascinating.
Um, explain basic superposition and so
on, basic entanglement. That is
fascinating. That will really generate a
lot of interest among the students. You
can do that without actually getting
into the into the math which students
may not uh have mastered clearly at the
you know in sixth seventh standard or
whatever. It it should be done in
actually it should be done. It will
expose way more students to the the
mysteries and and the beauty of science
of of physics of quantum mechanics
relativity and it may draw more people
into the fields that we need people to
go into. It should be done. But our see
that happens only when you have teachers
who are genuinely
passionate about what they're teaching.
If a teacher is genuinely passionate
about physics, quantum mechanics,
relativity, then that teacher will find
a way
to to to evoke that curiosity and
fascination among their students if they
genuinely love the subject and they
genuinely care about the students. But
most teachers in India don't care about
the subject. They don't care about the
damn students.
And the education system is run by
bureaucrats
and controlled by politicians. What do
you expect?
So that's one of the problems that we
have in India. Um UMXG Lola says I agree
with everything you say. Anything wrong
with me? Nothing wrong with you. Nothing
has such wrong with you. But try and
think of ways where I may be wrong or
maybe somebody else is wrong. Always try
and explore any issue from multiple
angles.
Right? For let me give you my own
example. Look until 2015 2016 I used to
believe in the Arian invasion theory. I
was a believer in that and when people
used to tell tell me on Twitter please
look into this it's wrong. I used to get
annoyed with them. Why do you have to
claim that everything came from India?
That was that's that was my approach.
That was my position at the time. Then
one day I asked myself let's look into
this. What if I am wrong?
And I looked into it. I spent several
months looking into it and I discovered
that what I believed was completely
wrong. Right? So you should always have
that
attitude approach whatever you want want
to call it. Always be willing to look at
things from different perspectives. And
if you discover that what you believe
was wrong, then you should be willing to
change your mind based on the new
information that you've got. Right?
>> [snorts]
>> that happens when you do deep dives into
topics, subjects, domains, whatever. So
yeah. Uh okay, VSVS is here. Swag to the
viewers. Namaste. Namaste G. You came,
you called, I came, was doing a dop
dopamine detox, therefore was abstaining
for supers. It's good to see you, sir.
You don't have to do supers. You have
done so many supers for so many other
people. you've been so kind to my
viewers and taken their questions and
put them on the super chat. So, thank
you so much. It's always good to have
you and please continue to dopamine
detox. You don't have to always be be
here. So, anyway, it's good to see you.
I'm glad that you're here. Please carry
on, sir. And thank you once again for
all the all the memberships you have
purchased for other people and so on.
Thank you so much. You are so incredibly
kind. It's so nice to have a viewer such
as you on the channel. Thank you so
much. Suga says, "Ask
ask you cause you really have a
knowledge of most things from physics to
history, from weather veas to chemistry.
How do you gather all of that?" How do I
gather all of that?
By reading.
Reading is a lost art today. Right?
Today
I'm not sure how people gain knowledge
today. Look, you can't gain knowledge
from watching book watching TV. You
can't gain knowledge from
you can't gain deep knowledge
from audio books. I'm not sure about
audio books. Audio books have never
worked for me. Podcasts can give you
an
entry-level kind of information about a
topic. See what I am doing ask
the best I can expect is that it will
spark some kind of curiosity or passion
about some some subject. Let's say I I
answered 50 questions today. Maybe three
of those you found fascinating and you
went and did some deep research. That's
the best I can expect. I can't actually
teach you the subjects over here, right?
I can simply share my perspectives and
understanding and whatever knowledge I
have with the hope that it will spark
some curiosity in you some of the
questions and then you will go and do
your own deeper research into that. So
how have I gathered knowledge about
various things?
By reading by reading in great detail
reading wide and reading deep.
So for example quantum mechanics I must
have studied more than 10 textbooks on
quantum mechanics at various levels you
start from Griffiths that's the entry-
level book right no even before that you
have
iceberg and restnik that's the that's
the book on modern physics or something
atomic yeah whichever it was it's been a
long time then you progress
so you have to do really deep dives into
things and also you have to need wide so
wide and deep and that takes time it
doesn't happen over over the period of 2
months that takes time long long long
time I've been reading all my life I
read my first novel when I was 7 years
old it took me seven days
so I have been a voracious reader
fiction non-fiction
physics history whatever everything that
I found interesting I read I still do so
that's how I do it takes a lot of work.
Yeah, it can. It's only fun if you if
you find it to be fun. I find it to be
fun. Aintan says, "What's your viewpoint
on the development of rail guns?
The Japanese have deployed it on JS
Osuka for sea trials in October 2025
whereas the US government has abandoned
it. Has the US really abandoned rail
guns?"
So, rail guns are
essentially rods that are propelled by
electromagnetic forces.
Okay. Um, and
they can these rods can be accelerated
to incredible speeds, you know, like way
beyond the speed of sound. Maybe Mach 2,
Mach 3, whatever. What's the average
speed of a rail gun? Yeah, let's find
out.
Uh rail rail gun average
rail gun speed.
Okay. Mark 6 to 10. Yeah. Okay.
So, military projectile mass projectile.
All that stuff. Yeah. Okay. Rail and how
do rail guns operate? Rail gun uh
basics.
Electroman. Yeah. Okay. Fine. So that
that's what I said. Yeah. So I was
right. U Yeah.
So I think it's a promising technology.
Obviously
see how rail guns are operated. You need
a long container kind of thing through
which you accelerate the the the
projectile. So and you need a lot of
energy.
So you won't have handgun sized rail
guns anytime soon. Uh, and if the
Japanese have been able to
miniaturaturize it and deploy it on a on
a ship, it means they have really taken
the technology to the next level, but
it's still an experimental technology.
Well, when I was a kid, lasers were an
experimental technology. They used to be
shown in James Bond movies,
right? Lasers, red lasers, slicing
through things. But today, lasers can be
used to take out missiles and aircraft.
So things have developed. Similarly,
rain rail gun technology also will
develop over time. I'm not sure if the
Americans have abandoned it. If they
have claimed that they've abandoned it,
maybe they are not being entirely
transparent about things. Okay. So I
think it's a promising technology. It
can be devastating
and uh yeah, but the only problem is
that you need a tremendous amount of
energy and a long long long acceleration
zone.
Shira Shinat says
can explain about the Kota Empireted
campaign across Indian subcontinent. He
has been excluded from our history.
The Kota Empire Lalita Muktapeda
he was the third king or something of
the Kota Empire. 7th 8th 9th centuries
AD probably 7th century AD after the
Gupta uh empire uh declined and and and
ended seventh or let's let's fact check
that and seekt
he was obviously a he was based in
Kashmir his capital was Shinagar and he
is said to have conquered various parts
of central Asia and also large parts of
the Indian subcontinent and he has been
definitely excluded from our history.
So uh let's go to Google in let's is it
7th or 8th century la
the former Maharaja of Kashmir?
Yeah. 8th century. That's right. Kota
monarch in the and and
Wikipedia will say that you know what he
didn't achieve much uh most powerful
king of his dynasty and so on. Uh yeah
conquest across India and central Asia.
Kalahhan says that and Kalahhan is a
pretty good source actually.
So yeah
I don't recall the exact chronology of
his empire and his reign. He was
definitely the most powerful king of the
dynasty
and u yeah right now I don't recall the
specific details of his career. I do
recall that he is said to have conquered
large parts of central Asia definitely
large parts of the subcontinent and he
has been totally excluded from our
history textbooks. Yeah, Kalhan writes
about him. Kalan is the great um
Kashmiri chronicler, the author of the
Raj Tarangini.
Uh
yeah the and after Lalita Muktapa died
his empire collapsed pretty rapidly. He
was the only great uh ruler of the
dynasty. That's what I can tell you
right now.
Uh I have in the past spoken about this
but right now this is what I can
remember.
So that's what I will be able to tell
you at this point in time.
Okay. MS Gaming says, "I waste my time
watching porn. How to control it?" I
don't know, sir. It's not an issue that
I have faced. So, I don't know. I've not
thought thought about this. So, I don't
know how to control it. I suppose you
stop doing what you want to suppose you
stop doing it.
Uh, is it that addictive?
Uh, I really don't know. Uh
if you want to break an addiction,
the best way to do it is to replace that
addiction with something positive that
you also enjoy that will not waste your
time. For example, lifting weights or I
don't know, find something that you
enjoy doing which will be which will
have a positive effect on your life and
not waste your time.
Excuse me. That's what I would
recommend. It's this is not a topic that
I've thought about so I am kind of
stumped when you ask me this question
but you know what yeah I suppose that's
what you could do so all the best sir
please uh stop doing stuff that is
wasting your time and not not good for
you all the best do well get rid of the
addiction all right sir all the best um
anan says Adi Aintua G said government
is bringing bringing a new bill to
target illegal conversions relate act
and once case has that whole life is
gone harsher than yapa. Okay, I'm not
aware of this but okay I'm not aware of
this.
Uh umxg lolha says hate reading books
becomes very boring gain knowledge
through scrolling in your insightful
videos please help.
I'll give you a solution. Don't read
boring books.
Okay let's say you find books boring.
find
the most
exciting
fiction book. Let's say for example, I
don't know, I don't know you personally,
but let's say hypothetically you like
spy thrillers,
okay? Or maybe you like action movies,
then find
the highest rated spy thriller book that
is available and read it. I promise you
that it will be a fast read. You will
enjoy it.
Or maybe you you are interested in
action movies. So find the best action
book novel. Make sure it's not a very
thick novel. Make it make it slim. Find
a slim one and read it. The more you
read, the faster you'll get at reading
and the more you'll be you'll be you'll
be able to enjoy it. Um so in my opinion
the best way to acquire knowledge is by
reading.
Okay? Reading is the best. Scrolling
will not give you knowledge my friend.
It will only give you very basic, very
superficial knowledge and understanding.
Um, my videos are obviously better than
scrolling, no question. But please take
my advice. Even better than for example
my videos is reading books.
So you can get some information from
what I am saying. I answer so many
questions. Obviously I'm not going into
great detail, but if I if you find
something interesting, find the right
book. even read five pages based on that
specific topic and you will get gain
more knowledge right
so read interesting books
initially don't read more than 10
minutes that works yeah that way you
will not be bored then over time you can
develop your tolerance and and your in
your stamina all right
says best beginner book for history
buffs now when you say history
which history are we talking
Are you talking about the history of the
world, history of India, history of
dinosaurs, history of butterflies? Which
history? There there's millions of
history books. Are you interested in
Indian history, Greek history, Roman
history, Mongol history, Chinese
history? Which history?
Um,
history of the First World War, Second
World War, natural history, history of
what? I I don't know. Oh, I'm I'm very
bad at doing book recommendations
because I've read so many books I can't
remember any of them. If I give you a
recommendation, you won't be able to
read it. I will say read the history the
story of civilization by Will Durant.
Okay. [laughter]
Uh the story of civilization.
Well, there you have it. This is the
greatest set of books on history that I
have read. I mean, I'm not sure if it's
if it is the greatest, but it had the
most impact on me when I was a kid. I
read these books when I was a kid. Most
of these Yeah. The story of civilization
by Will Durant and Ariel Durant. If you
are a history buff, you read these
books, you will gain more information
and knowledge than any other series of
books can give you. But these are not
exactly beginner books. Even though I
may have read it when I was a kid, these
are not exactly books for beginners, but
if you know, if you can persevere
through the books, they will give you so
much incredibly fascinating
information about history. So maybe
that's the that's
perhaps something you could look into.
Uh Amandari says, "What's your views on
Tom Clansancy books? Have I read Tom
Clansancy books?" Now, let me just
quickly see Tom Clansancy books. Uh Tom
Clansancy
books I've read so much stuff. Uh hunt
for red October. I've read of course
uh clear and present danger bear and
dragon executed devel authority.
Yeah. SSN choke point.
Um I think the only one I've read is The
Hunt for Red October which is a
fascinating outstanding brilliant book.
The more recent ones I'm pretty sure I
haven't read
without remorse into the storm locked on
against all Yeah, I think uh the hunt of
red october I have read and that's an
outstanding book and I think they have
made a outstanding movie based on that
book Sean Conry right uh yeah so he's
one of the great um authors writers of
spy thrillers like Alistair Mlean
I'm sure his books are pretty pretty
good. Yeah.
Okay.
Okay. Achi Anan says Lita Mukta died
while guiding his army out of a snow
blizzard in Uttaru. Okay.
Okay.
Thank you for that information. I will
uh look into that.
And that brings me to the end of today's
live stream. Oh, we have crossed three
hours. We have crossed the three hours.
All right.
So, let me bring an end to today's live
stream with this question that I just
answered. Thank you very much everybody
for the questions. I hope this was fun,
interesting. Maybe hopefully it gave you
some some good information
and I look forward to seeing you in the
live streams next week. Please always
keep learning, keep asking questions,
keep raising your standards, keep uh
watching these live streams and interact
interact interacting with me and I will
see you in next week's live streams and
this channel will will keep on putting
out clips of what we are discussing here
as always. So thank you very much
everybody. I look forward to seeing you
all very soon in the future live streams
and have a good night, good day, good
weekend. I'll see you soon. Thank you.
Bye-bye.